PAUL: Yeah, hello everyone, good morning.
PAUL: Please let me know, am I audible or not.
PAUL: All right, thanks for the confirmation.
PAUL: Alright, so let's talk about today's agenda.
PAUL: So I think this is my desktop.
PAUL: 3… Alright.
PAUL: Alright, so… in the last class…
PAUL: You have gone through the implementation, so, like, a little bit we'll be continuing the discussion with respect to hybrid search today.
PAUL: And your study even we discussed about Splate, which is a better version of sparse vector, as compared to static sparse vectors, like TFI, DF, and BM25.
PAUL: Okay, so little bit, today we'll be talking about the hybrid search, how to do the merging, because in the last class, in the formula, we have actually turned on that mean-max normalization, so that is one way, through this course that we can actually merge, so that particular concept we'll be looking into.
PAUL: So, the concept will come as RRF. I don't know how many of you have checked the notebooks. In the notebook, in the below part.
PAUL: of, fusion retrieval, you actually had the, core implementation of RRF that today we'll be going through.
PAUL: And then finally, we will jump into the re-ranking part.
PAUL: Okay, so exactly, the working of detranking, and very specifically, working with cross encoders. Okay, so that particular implementation and the theoretical part that we'll be focusing on.
PAUL: All right, guys, any questions till now? In the last class, the implementation, people, I think everybody…
PAUL: How many of you have done the implementation in the last class that I have shown first plan?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Have you tested it out with, multiple, models of Splat?
PAUL: Because I told you, please use the V3 version, where you'll be getting better scores. In last class, I remember Mahmoud was there, only he tested it out, and he shared the results. But others, anyone tested?
PAUL: the latest version… Please do test it out, okay, because really, like.
PAUL: Going forward, in your syllabus, though, I think, unified models are not there, but that particular concept, I am planning to take an extra class on Thursday, probably, and discuss that particular concept. So, using a single model, how to perform everything, tense search.
PAUL: Okay, you do need separate models for that.
PAUL: Alright, Splat, alright, this SPLAT got 2% increase. Alright, fine, there will be at least the improvement as per the newer one, because it has heart negative sampling. I remember that particular thing was there.
PAUL: In Splatv3. Okay, so for sure, whenever we go ahead with heart negative sampling, we get better results.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with our agenda. So, first of all.
PAUL: Rrf, okay, this particular concept, let's try to focus, okay, and then we'll be looking into the implementation. The implementation is directly available if you really look into that, Fusion retrieval notebook. So, in this particular notebook.
PAUL: I think, here you have that complete RRF implementation.
PAUL: Okay, so purely that.
PAUL: implementation, and it is, entirely from scratch, nothing with respect to land check, because there is a certain formula based on that formula, entirely all the implementation. So, pretty much a scratch one, if you really look into even… I've defined the cosine similarity formula.
PAUL: Okay, and I've used a simple TF idea. Now, we will try to understand exactly, because through this implementation also you can understand, because this is a scratch one, but let's try to take an example, and let's try to understand.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I think everyone is here. Okay, I think lesser people have joined today.
PAUL: As compared to other sessions.
PAUL: Alright, I think the new batch is also starting now, so probably a few people might have moved there also.
PAUL: So, let's open my iPad via cable, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so in the last class, the split version, we have gone through.
PAUL: Alright, so today, let's talk about…
PAUL: I think that's, that's a longer batch.
PAUL: Right.
PAUL: Okay, that I think, today only the timing is exactly the same.
PAUL: Nagavan yesterday will see the recording later. Alright, go through the recording.
PAUL: Not an issue Guys, so, let's start. I think everybody is ready.
PAUL: Entirely theoretical discussion, and there is no specific… all the notebooks are from the last class only, that we'll be talking about today.
PAUL: So, let's start the session.
PAUL: Let's take the green color.
PAUL: So, RRF. So, when I'm talking about it, it's reciprocal rank fusion, okay?
PAUL: to recycro.
PAUL: the rank.
PAUL: Fusion.
PAUL: Now, the question comes… Okay, whenever you are working.
PAUL: With a hybrid search. Okay, it means that in the hybrid search, you have two different types of search operations. One is your dense one.
PAUL: And one is your spot.
PAUL: Intense ones, directly I will say semantic search.
PAUL: And here you have a BM25 search. I am taking, for now, BM25, it can be split, it can be TFI gear, I hope everybody understands, okay? The idea is to find…
PAUL: Exact key matches or keyword matches.
PAUL: Now the question comes, how to combine the result. In the last implementation of Fusion Red Table, actually, I've written that formula, okay? Now, the question comes, how to do the merging? Two ways.
PAUL: managing?
PAUL: boot… The. Results.
PAUL: This is the main problem statement that I have.
PAUL: Can I say that both will have different dimensions, yes or no?
PAUL: each one… This pa- both of them will return.
PAUL: A list of ranked items.
PAUL: Probably, like, from the chunk perspective, if you really think about when you perform. In both the cases, you will be getting or not.
PAUL: Okay, now we have to think about the merging operations, so how to do the merge.
PAUL: So, first of all, we'll be talking with respect to this RRF what. Now, here, RRF plays a crucial role, okay?
PAUL: Now, with respect to merging, you have to think about
PAUL: two different ways that we can merge. First of all, one can be based on score, and the other one can be based on rank.
PAUL: Okay, so two ways.
PAUL: Yes, can I say this?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Everyone, okay? Two ways of doing this.
PAUL: So, right now, I will be discussing about the first one, the rank version, which is the reciprocal rank, okay, and then I will come to that other one.
PAUL: which is the RSF, that particular implementation also, like, and the theoretical part you will be going through. So, RRF, it has a simple formula that you have to remember, because here, we will be only playing with the ranks, okay? In RRF,
PAUL: We only play… with the ramps.
PAUL: Not with schools. It doesn't matter what is the school that is coming.
PAUL: It will be purely based on the ranch.
PAUL: Now, Mitesh is asking, but ranking will be different, how to compare sales ranking on each of them? Yes, I'll be talking about that. So, ranking will be different, for sure. The same document can be ranked different in a dense search, as well as it can be different in a sparse search, the same document.
PAUL: Now, with respect to when I'm talking about the rank place, so let's talk about it. It has a very simple formula.
PAUL: Okay, I'm writing Y simple, just write formula here.
PAUL: So, as we'll be focusing on the rank, the formula will be 1 divided by
PAUL: Her constant K will come, okay? With that, we'll be simply adding the rank for that particular document that we'll be getting. Now, K is a constant.
PAUL: Okay, and in most of the implementations, I have seen that they take it as 60.
PAUL: Always remember this. Now, when you look into this formula, what you can understand.
PAUL: So, for example, let's take a document, because the idea is let's take a E… Document that you have.
PAUL: Now, in that, particular, document.
PAUL: Like, I can say that based on, two different types of results. Okay, so one can be from dens. Let's take…
PAUL: List A. Okay, so this is probably happening.
PAUL: And a list P for now.
PAUL: One is for tense, the other one is for sparse. Really, like, right now, the schools doesn't matter. So, simply, it's totally based on the rank that I have.
PAUL: Alright, now, based on the formula, yes, in… not directly inversely, professional, okay, the idea is that top-ranked
PAUL: Dogs, or basically the chance, they won't be very dominant.
PAUL: Okay? That is the idea. So, let's take some values right now.
PAUL: No, if, in both the cases, if you are having, based on some type of documents.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, I will just simply put the formula in that particular formula. If I take my 1,
PAUL: divided by…
PAUL: K, the value of K will be 60, plus the rank that I'm getting. Okay, so probably I'm getting 1 in this case. Now here, probably, I'm getting
PAUL: Let's take 5. Then, what will be the scores? So, similarly, something in decimal values that I'll be getting, so this will be probably, I think, 0 point, somewhere around. Okay, exact calculation, I think around 16…
PAUL: Okay, just wait, let me see where I've written it previously.
PAUL: One… So I think this is 154, and this is 164.
PAUL: Alright? Now, a single document, can I say that it might have been different? Because, for sure, both the results won't be showing you the same results. Now, this particular thing that you have got, simply try to combine it, as simple as that. Let's try to combine both the scores.
PAUL: When you try to combine it, simply you have to perform an addition operation of this one, 0.0154, and based on that, the output that we'll be getting, it will be close to 0.318.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this is a simple example of a document when I'm talking.
PAUL: Is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: Very much simple operation, because it's directly on top of the rank that you were claiming.
PAUL: And you are not playing anything with respect to the schools.
PAUL: Yes. Now, let's take, now, can you tell me what is the benefit of this?
PAUL: when you actually take this, because this is a simple formula. When there is, a simple formula you have, it means that you don't need any type of learning. So, few benefits it has.
PAUL: One is basically no tuning required, I can say.
PAUL: Aruna is asking, rank of dense or spas. This is the final combined result.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is this is the merged version, the combined version.
PAUL: Yes, combined will be for the same document, the niche.
PAUL: I have, right now, the example I've taken, in both the places, they are getting different ranks. So, both on their tracks, I am just trying to do a simple merge operation.
PAUL: Yes, one list is basically the representation of a tense, and the other one is a representation of a sparse.
PAUL: Look, a single document can have a different rank in both the search operations and the test, so based on that, directly on top of the formula, I've just set the settings, and based on that, I've calculated the combined scores.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: For everyone. Alright, now let's move. So, here, it directly works, like, out of the box, because it's a simple TED formula.
PAUL: Now, nothing related to score, so I can say score agnostic.
PAUL: Okay And now…
PAUL: The other benefit that you have… so, for example, if there is a bad retriever, okay, so that won't get dominance. Like, this is, that's why this is widely used, RRF.
PAUL: Okay, so if you have any type of bad retriever, so probably you might have, like, one is retrieving good, the other might be bad. In that case, the bad retriever cannot dominate.
PAUL: Alright, so remember, so this is…
PAUL: I can say, you have no domination.
PAUL: Of a single retriever.
PAUL: Because here you have two different retrievers.
PAUL: Alright, yes, I think it will be 03, I have missed the 0, sorry for that. Yes.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, let's try to take an example, and let's try to take multiple documents.
PAUL: I will simply create a table, okay? So, and then, one column I'll be taking only for tents.
PAUL: One column I'll be taking for sparse.
PAUL: Okay? And the, final scores that you will have, okay, later on, this table I will update. So, simply take, let's say 4 documents, 1, 2, 3, 4. Okay? Now, in the dense part for, documentative I'm talking about.
PAUL: This is your doc A. Now, here you'll be having, should I write ABCD?
PAUL: This is Doctor Street.
PAUL: Doc. Doc. Doc.
PAUL: Alright, I think ABCD, I can directly take it. Okay, and here, let's take C or D on the top.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, simply, I have taken this particular setting right now, okay? Now… Yes.
PAUL: Now, when you have this particular document, so if I want to calculate the scores for each document, right now, because in the last example, a single document that I have taken. Now, let's do it for document A.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Calculate RF. Okay, document A.
PAUL: F.
PAUL: So, what will be the value?
PAUL: Truly, tell me, guys.
PAUL: You have to calculate using the same formula for both. Okay, so let's do it for the first one, later on you guys can do the calculation.
PAUL: So, document AR is the value. So, one I'll be doing for tens, D, and S. Now, in this formula, what you have? 1,
PAUL: divided by… 60, plus… 1.
PAUL: Because document A, with respect to DEN search, it has rank 1. In the next step, it has rank 2.
PAUL: Okay, so 1 divided by 60 plus 2. Now, whatever the value that you will be getting, okay, I think it will be somewhere close to 0.1, and this will be close to 0.161.
PAUL: Okay, I think this is… Okay, somebody told in chat it is 6-4, fine.
PAUL: Now, total value that you'll be getting from here…
PAUL: What will be the total value? 0.0325.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Similarly, do the calculation for document, I think you can do for B, document C, okay, and document D.
PAUL: Okay, once I have the final results, then simply I can perform what? A sort operation.
PAUL: Based on the
PAUL: Okay? So simply, guys, tell me quickly for B, okay? So, okay, I'm showing you this table. Do you guys do the calculation by yourself.
PAUL: I think this part, probably a little bit, I will change it to DMT, yes.
PAUL: quickly do the calculation, guys. Quickly, it will tell me for document A, what is the final score? For document C, what is the final score? And Document D, what is the final score?
PAUL: Typek is asking, what is K? K is… in the formula, we have that K, where I have taken K is equal to 60. So, typically, for 60 to oxide, we generally do.
PAUL: Okay, so that is pretty much in every implementation I have seen K, the value of K is taken as 60.
PAUL: Truly, let me know, guys, for document B, what is the value that you are getting?
PAUL: step by step, do it for B, do it for C, and do it for T.
PAUL: We will leave documents… we will leave documents which are available only in any one of the lists. No, no, it's not about leaving out the documents in each.
PAUL: Okay, for B, somebody is telling me the score that you are getting is…
PAUL: 0.0317, alright, let me write B…
PAUL: The final RRF score for B is… Aruna is telling 0.0328.
PAUL: Satya Narayana's telling 0.0319.
PAUL: And… okay, like, everybody has told a different score.
PAUL: Our widget is telling 0. Okay, 0.3.
PAUL: Which is good I am writing, others can confirm that, okay?
PAUL: Now, for your CRRF,
PAUL: Okay, because 0.37 can be 0.38, I'm not worried about that, but there should not be a lot of difference.
PAUL: Alright, for C, okay, you…
PAUL: Telling 0.0322, okay? So, C, alright, 0.
PAUL: 0322, and somebody are telling 0.23. Fine, 2322, pretty much close, I can say.
PAUL: And what is the final score for document D?
PAUL: Okay, Viraj is telling 0.03.
PAUL: 1-5… okay, 1, 2, 5, somebody is telling.
PAUL: 1, 2, 5. All right. Alright, I am taking 1, 2, 5.
PAUL: 0.03125… Okay, 1, 2, 5… alright.
PAUL: Now, the final fused ranking, what you'll be getting.
PAUL: Okay, so the final… Fused a lank.
PAUL: B, C… Indeed.
PAUL: So, out of this, which one is having the highest score?
PAUL: Document A, 0.0325172312, okay? So, I know my top score is for Document A, 0.0325.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so here, simply, I can write 0.0325 for this. Then, for your B document, it was 0.
PAUL: The 0317. For your seat is…
PAUL: Okay, this is… I think C is having much more hair, okay? I will just, change this person.
PAUL: to C, okay, and let's make this one as B.
PAUL: Thank God.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, for your B, what is the value? 0.03… 0.0317. Let me change the value here. It's 0.0323 that you were getting. And for your D, I will say that you have the least value.
PAUL: Okay, so can you, see here the final, ranked version that I have? Okay, from this particular table, okay, in both the searches, based on the rank. Now, your final results.
PAUL: After applying, RRF, I hope everybody gets it. What will be your top documents?
PAUL: Simple yes or no.
PAUL: Okay, and simply if you, really looked into the results of this particular, search also, here I can actually look into that dense part for documentation is in the top. Okay, as well as in the sparse also, it is in the second. So, for sure, we know that it will be having a higher position as compared to others.
PAUL: But, with respect to Document C, directly during 10 search, okay, it actually dropped. So, because of that, somewhere it came around the result, like, close to second. But 10 search of B was better, but the sparse result was very bad. So you can really look around in both the stages.
PAUL: Alright, now, I hope everybody understood the sample implementation.
PAUL: Alright, Dinesh is asking, let's assume if you have even 10 lakh, doesn't matter. If you want that K value, always you can change it, then it's not necessary 60. I am taking majorly lakh 16, major implementation.
PAUL: If you have that, you can increase that number, Dinesh. There are no limitations in that.
PAUL: Aruna, can we use different embedding techniques and views? Really, like, embedding techniques, why it matters.
PAUL: Yes, this is not a stone value, Nitesh.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: In most of the academic studies, but later on in implementation, this value sometimes gets changed, really.
PAUL: Alright, now, embedding, really, Aruna, that doesn't matter, your embedding techniques. I can say that the performance or the quality of that embedding can be better for dense, so for sure, if the results of the dense search and the spar search
PAUL: It's affected, so for sure the rank will also be affected.
PAUL: So, if you are working with a decent model, usually I… mostly there will be very, very huge difference.
PAUL: The difference comes, really, like, 2-3% difference will be there.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, Cynthia, can there be any extra document that's present in this, but not in sparse? Why there will be an extra document, Cynthia?
PAUL: If you have a dataset for that particular dataset, when you actually try to pick it, it won't be different.
PAUL: Like, once you have created the chance, on top of those chunks, you'll be applying. So, for sure, it won't be. The length of the document will always remain the same.
PAUL: Okay, Nitesh, alright, good, it's for understanding, empirical formula, okay, those things you have written, it's good.
PAUL: JVY60, because according to academics, we know the number, the 60, but again, it's not a fixed one. You can always change this number. For example, if in the ranked results you are working with more and more documents, then it can make it to 100 and 200.
PAUL: Okay, alright, will, not be more importance in RF? Will it not be more importance in RF with respect to what, Matesh, you were telling?
PAUL: Methish is asking, what about one document retrieve in top K of dense, but not in sparse?
PAUL: At least in sparse, it will have some rank, no.
PAUL: It will have some rank. It cannot… it is not possible that it won't have rank only.
PAUL: And generally, it doesn't happen if something with respect to the dense search, it is in the top position. In the sparse such, it will be in the last position. Practically not possible, Mitesh.
PAUL: Okay, now, practically, it is possible if you create such a
PAUL: like, very, very bad algorithm, like monot encoding or something like that, it may perform, but again, at least it won't be the last time. Any embedding techniques that we have learned. So, Vash, if you have, score, if we have same score, right now I'm not talking about score, so Vash, so why you are asking this question.
PAUL: I'm only worried about rants. RRF only deal with respect to rants.
PAUL: JB, how we are comparing the chunks? We are not doing a comparison only.
PAUL: Here, we are nothing, we are not doing any comparison. How many of you feel that we are doing any comparison?
PAUL: Hari, any few real-time examples where we'll be using fusion retrieval? I… in most of the rack systems, hybrid search is a pretty common one, and ARR is widely used.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Already, yes, the rank that you were talking about, it will be coming with respect to scores only, but they will have the rank. Right now, I'm only worried about the ranks.
PAUL: I'm not worried about the score.
PAUL: Based on the scores, you get the ranks, but I'm not worried about the scores.
PAUL: Simple.
PAUL: I hope you get that, Subhash. Jb, I mean Doc8s and doc SARS. How we are relating? We are not relating anything, we are just looking into the rank of each… that same document in both the list.
PAUL: As simple, like, probably in the dense as well as in the sparse, and based on that particular rank, we are simply creating a fusion.
PAUL: There is no relating here.
PAUL: Nitesh, are we passing the same query doc?
PAUL: how are we passing the same query slash doc? Query slash doc, neither we are passing the query, neither we are passing any doc.
PAUL: Okay? Then, two multiple retrievers. For example, you have two retrievers. One is a dense retriever, the other one is a sparse retriever. Now, from there, you'll be getting the results. In both the results, you'll be getting the rats. Now, on top of those two, final, results of dense sparse, you are applying a simple fusion technique.
PAUL: Arunai, you can do that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: As simple as that. There is no such thing that you were telling about with respect to that implementation, taking a weight at someone, something like that.
PAUL: Doc A, are we referring correct?
PAUL: dock A, we are referring as chunk. These are chunks.
PAUL: These are chunks, guys. This is a chunk, this is a chunk, this is a chunk, this is a chunk. What is the output of a retriever?
PAUL: The output of a retriever is what? Chunks only, no? For every chunk, you get ranked with scores. Yes, guys, please tell me.
PAUL: Please tell me that.
PAUL: How many of you get? Don't think about document as a PDF document.
PAUL: The output of a retriever is what?
PAUL: Junk.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Fine. Now, Based on this particular implementation, let's, get back.
PAUL: To our implementation that we have taken, so let me just stop.
PAUL: With respect to the weightage value, you can, work around, around, like, 0.5 is a good number, deba.
PAUL: 0.55 also, I've seen 0.6 also, with respect to that alpha parameter, you can always play with those.
PAUL: Alright, now let's come to this screen.
PAUL: This is that one.
PAUL: Now, this is a Scratch implementation, entirely that I have taken. Okay.
PAUL: Mom.
PAUL: Here, in the reciprocal rank fusion, you can see the rankings will be basically one of the inputs.
PAUL: K is equal to 60, and right now, weights is equal to none that I have taken.
PAUL: Okay, so, two simple conditions, if weight is equal to none, and based on that, the poor formula of power that have been defined. Now, the document shows, right now, here.
PAUL: that I have taken it as a blank list, and this is a simple version on top of which, on every RRF score that I'll be calculating. Okay, RRF score, when I'm talking about what think I'm actually using the score values, rather than I'm using the rhin's.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, once we get the result, on top of the document source, I'll be performing a sort operation. Okay, so based on that, simply I have applied it.
PAUL: Now, this particular function, so here I have taken a few sample tops.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And, a simple query.
PAUL: Now, I'm creating dense embeddings directly using sentence transformers, or mini-LM embedding model.
PAUL: Okay, now this…
PAUL: particular, I can say, tense model that I am passing, right? So that I'll be getting my document embeddings.
PAUL: Okay? And then, finally, encoding it with respect to our query also, because both the things needs to be encoded. This is only for our dens search. Then we have a simple cosine similarity definition that I have done.
PAUL: Okay? Now, coming to the ranking of the documents, so whatever the…
PAUL: results that I'll be getting from… and right now, as you can see here, I'm passing.
PAUL: And through that, I'm looking into that. The final result, I'll be passing it through a list. So, this is the dense ranking. Everything is a custom implementation, guys. Okay?
PAUL: So this is exactly how it even works within the rack. Through NumPy, I am performing the arc sort, but sometimes in GPU-based libraries, this operation can be based with respect to Torch or KRAS-based also.
PAUL: Now, this entire thing is related to what? Whatever the things that I have done, this is pure.
PAUL: Dense retrieval.
PAUL: Okay? Now, in the next step, I need to do the same thing for sparse retrieval.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the implementation, so here I've taken TF IDM. Purely, I'm not working with BM25, just kept the implementation simple.
PAUL: Okay, now finally, let's try to combine both the results. So, here I am actually calling my function.
PAUL: Okay? The reciprocal rank fusion, and the input to this particular function in the params ranking was defined, so both the ranking that I am passing, dense ranking, sparse ranking, K is equal to 60, and here.
PAUL: Okay, so I am passing that particular parameter. Okay, so here, I have not taken any normalized values, anything between 0 to 1. Okay, but as you can see, I've given more of it each. Okay, 2.0 and 1.0. So, similarly, you can pass 3.0 also here.
PAUL: The idea is that to give more weightage to then search, always, as compared to sparse. So, the value of the alpha parameter, it should be most of the times.
PAUL: 30 0.5 or more than that. Nevertheless.
PAUL: Okay, so finally I will be getting the results, so if I try to process this…
PAUL: It will take some time for the processing, I think.
PAUL: Okay, Natish is telling, so I understand the user query, the process begins when a user passes a question on the multiple retrievers, the query is sent to the sparse and the tense retriever, correct?
PAUL: Individual rankings, each retriever produces its own rank, exactly correct. RRF fusion, the ranking from the retrievers are combined with the RRF order, exactly correct. Then final ranking is the unified ranking, okay, on top of the RRF fusion values that you perform that sort operation.
PAUL: And finally, the generative model, use the top right. Correct, Nitesh, all those steps that you have pulled.
PAUL: Alright, now, based on, the results, if you really look into… Okay, so here, this is my machine learning, it's a subset of AI, so what is an AI? Based on that, I'm getting the result.
PAUL: In the sparse, also, I'm getting. So, for sure, I know the, I can say the document 0 for now. Okay, that will be always having higher rank.
PAUL: Okay, so here, as you can see, machine learning. So, for sure, this is producing much more higher ranks compared to the others. So, if you really look into… So, here, computer vision enables machines to interpret images. So, like, what is AI? Really, the term AI was not used directly here, only in this term, you can see AI.
PAUL: Okay, other than that, I don't think anywhere else. Now, AI with respect to ML part, this machine learning is one of the keywords, so for sure, I think, enables machines, I feel, somewhere, it has given much more focus to this. Computer vision enables machines to interpret images.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, this is the pure core implementation. Now, how many of you got the implementation? The same thing in theory that I have told you, I've applied it purely. Here, nothing langshan, nothing Lama-ended, because it's purely a simple mathematical formula.
PAUL: Guys, please let me know.
PAUL: Motazar is asking how we identify that chunk 1 in both
PAUL: In both the reserves, whenever you are performing a retrieval, whether using sparse or dense, in both the cases, chunk 1 will have some rank in your dense retrieval, and chunk 1 will have some rank in your sparse module. It will always be there, because the total number of chunks, it is fixed once you have processed the document.
PAUL: Dinesh, yes, RRF is one of the methods to create hypotheses, not to create. The idea is to merge the reserves of your dense and sparse.
PAUL: Retriever.
PAUL: Because the keyword machine is there, JB.
PAUL: And, its rank is 4 in each. Where it is 4? This computer part here, it's 2nd, and here it's third.
PAUL: Please at least look, okay, Chang1Chang can be at different ranks.
PAUL: Chunk 1 slash chunk A. Alright, you are talking about a single chunk A, so it can be at different ranks. We are using those ranks only to calculate, no?
PAUL: The final score that I'm calculating for RRF, it is totally based on those rack.
PAUL: Right now, I'm taking chunk 1 is equal to chunk and moved the other.
PAUL: Sir, is RRF just a form of stacking the framework?
PAUL: stacking framework, like we use in ML Ensemble. This is not purely an assemble-based approach. You can think about assembling we are doing, but assemble of the retrievers much more. That's the only thing.
PAUL: Generally, try to give always more weightage, to your tenure search. Okay, at least 0.5 or more than that.
PAUL: That is suggested. Narula.
PAUL: This… all right here, both sparse and dense, both are giving, which is better. Yes, it can give you a shiny buzz. There is no…
PAUL: Fixie, when I look into this final result, I cannot say directly, by looking into that, why this is happening. When you actually have 1,000, 10,000, really, you cannot decide that. Right now, for 5 examples, you can actually visualize that.
PAUL: But really, when the number of docs keeps on increasing, it is not possible.
PAUL: Alright, should we set on one more time?
PAUL: Can you tell about the VPs? So, generally, for the densarch always gives, like, more than 50% priority to that.
PAUL: At least 50 or more than 50.
PAUL: In real time, which one should you use?
PAUL: Which one? I am only taught one.
PAUL: Always, guys, remember the first priority always goes to hybrid, the first priority always goes to your then search.
PAUL: Then comes your hybrid search. So, in most of the RAG systems, I feel that everybody enables hybrid search by default, because really, the process is not really a time-taking process.
PAUL: Okay, so RRF is very, very common.
PAUL: Alright, I hope everybody got the fundamental working of RRF.
PAUL: There is a doubt of previous chat? What is the previous chat, Subhas?
PAUL: I have no idea. Share the previous set.
PAUL: Okay, so here you are telling documented vectors, is equal to semantic
PAUL: Again, while we are talking with scores.
PAUL: Okay, now based on the scores, are you referring to the ranks?
PAUL: Right now, I'm talking about ranks, I'm not worried about the scores.
PAUL: Always write that bank.
PAUL: Now, based on scores, you can refer the rank in dense search.
PAUL: Alrighty, yes, Document A, Document C can have same scores. I can understand that. Now, do you feel that the same scores will be there in your sparse also?
PAUL: Yes. Okay, now, this is a valid question. It means that you are telling for both of the chunks, you are getting the same semantic score.
PAUL: Okay? Let's agree with that. Now, do you feel that
PAUL: For, chunk A and chunk B will have the same score for your sparse also.
PAUL: So, boss, tell, quickly.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Show me an example by doing an implementation.
PAUL: the sparse value, really, that will be different. It has to be different.
PAUL: Semantic score can always be very, very similar, or at least with respect to decimal values, I know. Somehow, it will be different.
PAUL: Actually, when you take a float off that, if you just write 0.92, I can understand, fine. But after .0.92, there are other values also.
PAUL: The thing that you were telling me, practically, it's not.
PAUL: Okay, now, simply, like, if you really think about, in both the cases, everything is…
PAUL: in the top, it means that document A
PAUL: is having the same score, Document B is also having the same score, Document C is also having the same score. Okay, and even in search also, you are getting document ABC. I don't think the algorithm works in that way. That everywhere you will be getting the same score.
PAUL: Mmm… Okay, yes, so… Does chunks from the same document appear and crowd others?
PAUL: chunk from the same document appear and crowd others, if he is…
PAUL: Like, same document crowd can happen. If within that crowd you have that particular query-based context.
PAUL: So, yes, for sure, the other chance.
PAUL: I cannot say it as a crowd, so what do you exactly mean by a crowd? Do you refer to noise?
PAUL: semantic search can never be exactly the same, I know that. Because with respect to cosine distance, really, in the same 3D dimensional space, the same point on top of that point, it can never overlap. Always remember that.
PAUL: Alright, so I hope this part is clear. Please let me know, guys, can we proceed ahead?
PAUL: Can we proceed ahead for the next part? Please let me know.
PAUL: Got it, a fraction 10 value, yes, that fraction, again, your floating values. That's the thing I told you, no.
PAUL: In higher dimensional space, okay, on top of the same set, it can be close, I can say, it can be very close, but exactly not on top of each other.
PAUL: Practically not personal.
PAUL: Alright, now, let's talk about, another approach a little bit.
PAUL: Okay, so… now, the approach that I have told, this is with respect to, rants much more. Okay, the other way, let's look around, which is sports now.
PAUL: Okay, now, and then finally, a little bit comparison that I'll be giving you with respect to schools in this one. Okay, so let's get back to the notes.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: I remember, like, in one of the interviews, when it was asked to me.
PAUL: I was actually giving the interview for a startup, they asked me with respect to RRF.
PAUL: And that was, again, back in 2023.
PAUL: Oof… Slide striking iPad via cable… alright, this one.
PAUL: So sometimes, yes, in the interview with us, I feel that this is a much easier implementation, so anybody can remember.
PAUL: Because, really, the formula is very simple, and practically, anybody can do the implementation.
PAUL: Alright, so the next one, the next topic, okay, a little bit, now I'll be changing from rank to school this time.
PAUL: No, it was not for a data science engineer.
PAUL: It was for senior gen AI.
PAUL: Gotcha.
PAUL: Alright, now, our next implementation, now I will be playing with this course. Last time I played with this, guns, so, now this particular formula, okay, we refer to that RSF.
PAUL: Okay, so let's take this one.
PAUL: Tink…
PAUL: Okay, the name is very, very simple. Okay, so here, when you look into R, there is no reciprocal, just be sure. Okay, it is Relative Score Fusion Net, we call it.
PAUL: Okay, so it stands for… Relative.
PAUL: Or… Fusion.
PAUL: Right? Now, here, we will totally, like, I can say.
PAUL: As you remember, in RRF, we totally ignored the scores, we only focused on the rats, okay? This time, I'll be playing.
PAUL: Almost renewables, that is also fine, but at least one time showing that as an example.
PAUL: That was the idea.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, I mean, did you enable Chris, line by line, compared against the formula? No, these are standard implementations across multiple academic papers and other…
PAUL: always, like, and most of the implementation is a direct function call, but within that function, if you really go through, you can actually look into the simple implementation, because the implementation is really, that low level. Everywhere, I feel that the same implementation is there.
PAUL: Alright guys, so now let's focus on RSI. Okay, now here, we're only focusing on scores, no rank. It means that this time, I will play
PAUL: with schools.
PAUL: forget rank.
PAUL: So simply, here I will write… No rank here.
PAUL: Can I say that in both the cases, you will be getting scores, yes or no?
PAUL: Okay, so if I say that, I'll be getting some type of raw scores.
PAUL: Okay, and really, the scale doesn't matter. Okay, when I'm talking with respect to the raw scores, so from our vector, I will be having something, okay? So, let me write 20, okay, and as vec.
PAUL: And I'll be having something.
PAUL: So, if you want to do… can I say the scale is same? The dimension, with respect to the list, can I say that?
PAUL: Will it be same or not? Think.
PAUL: It is not same. Always remember that. How it can be same, guys.
PAUL: the output Okay, it won't be. They are… they are not directly comparable. Always remember, not directly comparable.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, the first thing, correct ATK. We need to perform a normalization operation.
PAUL: Okay, so simply, the first step that comes here is your normalization.
PAUL: For normalization, you need to have that mean-max value, so the idea is to bring something in between 0 to 1.
PAUL: Now, to get the normalized score, what is the formula? Okay, so N underscore score, if I write.
PAUL: Simply. Right now, again, here the formula will come. So, for that particular document. Now, this is for a single document right now.
PAUL: Score minus your mean score that you will have.
PAUL: Now, that will be divided by, according to your… Normalization formula.
PAUL: Max score?
PAUL: With that, again, I will perform a subtraction with respect to our mean score.
PAUL: Fair.
PAUL: Okay, now the division is there. Now, this is a simple formula. This will return what?
PAUL: And I say this will return.
PAUL: The normalized version.
PAUL: The normalized score for that particular document.
PAUL: Yes or no, quickly say to me, this is simple normalization. In the entire field of data science, we perform this. There is nothing in you here.
PAUL: Hari's asking, dense based on framework. Dense based on framework, based on number of documents in the repo.
PAUL: Based on… not the number of documents, rather think from the chunk perspective.
PAUL: Every document, there will be chunks, thinking in that way. And based on frameworks, intense based on framework, based on the num… really, why we're thinking the number of chunks
PAUL: That will be same for dense, that will be same for sparse, and it won't be different.
PAUL: Alright. Now, with respect to the… this is the first part, okay. Now, the idea is that we will perform the normalized scores across the result of the retrievals.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, the final thing that we'll be trying to do, so we will try to sum up, okay, the normalized scores.
PAUL: Across?
PAUL: All retrievables.
PAUL: Okay. Similarly, in RRF also, it's not necessary you have only 2 retrievers. There can be 3 retrievers also.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: You can use a third retriever.
PAUL: Now, let's try to take a very similar example, and then we will try to debug the same thing. So, first of all, let's look into the raw results.
PAUL: In both the cases.
PAUL: Let's take… so this time, again, I'll be taking, so… Okay. Document… Let's take the dense.
PAUL: Okay, I'll sparse.
PAUL: I think I need the dock value also.
PAUL: Okay, so, based on, the dog values, so let's take dock A.
PAUL: I need to give some score here. Okay, so probably, like, 0.92.
PAUL: Then for doc P, like, all the values, let me just type it. Look, I kept this one.
PAUL: what could be?
PAUL: 0.85, 0.71, and 0.68.
PAUL: Okay? So, these values that I have taken. Now, for the other one, with respect to sparse, let me take document CF something.
PAUL: Okay, the scales will be different, so talk.
PAUL: 14.2, then finally coming to talk, your 10.8.
PAUL: 19… Your final doc, that you have.
PAUL: Which is 7.1. Okay, so it's here, document C,
PAUL: Then you have your document A, D, and P.
PAUL: You get CADB, just like last time we have done.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Anal, what is the first thing?
PAUL: What is the mean and max value? Could you tell me here?
PAUL: For a dense search, first of all, tell me what is the mean and max value. I am doing it for, first, dense.
PAUL: Okay, let me write here, max.
PAUL: The max value that I have is 0.92. Directly for document A, I can see, and the minimum value that I have is 0.68. Now, I will just calculate for document A, reset document A.
PAUL: Now, according to the formula, the same formula that I have written it here, you can apply it here.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, for documentary, when I'm calculating the max value, I think 0.92, then, I will subtract it with the lower one, 0.68, simple normalization operation, divided by…
PAUL: 0.92 minus 0.68.
PAUL: Yes, this value will come exactly as what?
PAUL: Quickly, tell me what will be the value here. Okay, it's easy to calculate, so I'm asking.
PAUL: Okay? Similarly, do the calculation for document…
PAUL: Bcd. Okay, and tell me the values.
PAUL: Okay, A and I'm writing, like.
PAUL: What is the value for document B? It is 0.85, so let's write 0.85 here, minus 0.68, this value won't be changing, divided by 0.92.
PAUL: Yes, and then finally, minus 0.68, so from here, I'll be getting the value gross to 0.7.
PAUL: Okay, so for B also I have done, please do it for CND, and then quickly tell me the way.
PAUL: do the calculations at least by yourself. I feel that going forward, it will be to remember.
PAUL: Okay, the value of C, alright, somebody is today, it's…
PAUL: 0.13, alright, it's fine, it's 0.125 PUNAM, okay, we will see.
PAUL: The value 0.125.
PAUL: Okay, 125 is also fine, 13 is also fine, rigid.
PAUL: Cynthia, 0.125, correct, Viraj. Okay, let's do it for Documentee.
PAUL: D0?
PAUL: No, don't.
PAUL: Now, let's calculate the sparse one, okay? So, look into this. Similarly, I think you guys can do the calculation for sparse.
PAUL: Okay, I will do it for here, 18.5 is the first one. Okay? So, remember the values here, I'll be showing you later on. Now, I will do it for sparse.
PAUL: What was the first document? The first document is actually Document C, so let's start from Document C.
PAUL: that I have.
PAUL: Okay, so here, what was the value? The value that I have is 18.5, okay? So I will just write here 18.5, okay, and let me write the mean and max also.
PAUL: for you, it will be easier to calculate. The mean value that I have is 7.21, and the max value that I have is, I think, 18.5 only.
PAUL: Now, based on this, so 18.5, Minus 7.1 that you have.
PAUL: Divided by 18.5 minus 7.1…
PAUL: Okay. Which comes close to 1 only. Then we'll literally do it for the other docs. Please look into this table, document A.
PAUL: Okay, so document C that you have, so if you are confused with that, this is Document C, this is A, this is D, and this is B. So, do in this particular format only, C, A, D, P.
PAUL: Alright, for documents here, I've already done it.
PAUL: Okay, so for document… E.
PAUL: Okay, people are telling.
PAUL: 0.622, alright, 0.622.
PAUL: for document next one that you have, which is D.
PAUL: and B.
PAUL: This data point.
PAUL: 3, 2, alright, 0.32 JV. For B again, it will be 0, alright.
PAUL: Okay? Now, we have this table. Now…
PAUL: Once we have this table, so what is the next thing that we will try to do?
PAUL: Okay, so let's create a new table this time.
PAUL: No, I think why the same color is here and here?
PAUL: Let's take a different one, I think.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: So, with respect to our new table that I have, little bit reform.
PAUL: Now, based on the scores, I will try to perform, so let's take Document A.
PAUL: B, C, and D. So first, with respect to dense, You already have the values?
PAUL: And here, with respect to sparse.
PAUL: Now, based on the results, okay, so… what is the value getting for document A? If you remember, it was 1.
PAUL: Okay? But document B,
PAUL: or document C, like, which one is having. So, when you look into this one, document A was 1, then, document B was 0.71.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: So, and C was having 0125, okay, so, fine. So, B was having…
PAUL: I think this ranking I should do based on the, dense version only, okay? So, a little bit change that target only.
PAUL: Here, let me bring C… B, okay, Andy.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: 1, 0.125 that I will have.
PAUL: Now, the value of B was 0.71, and finally D, it was 0. Similarly, D, in the other case, B was having 0 here, so let me directly write a 0.
PAUL: For D, the spools that we had is 0.32, 0.32… for, yeah, it was around 0.62.
PAUL: And, this is around 0. I think the next one is…
PAUL: C is actually 1, okay?
PAUL: So, alright, here I have one.
PAUL: Now, this is based on the normalized pose, I've just reformed that, okay. Now…
PAUL: for calculating your RF scope, the final column that you will have.
PAUL: Okay, so here I will write sum of normalized schools.
PAUL: Okay, now…
PAUL: I will be doing a simple addition operation. So, here, if you want… okay, let me just, write it here only, okay? A new column that I'm creating, this is for your del, this is for your spouse, okay, this is based on the document.
PAUL: Now, your RSF value, 1 plus 0.62, 1.62.
PAUL: Okay, then you have, 1.125.
PAUL: Then you have your V value, which is 0.71. Okay, and finally, if you look into here, 0.32.
PAUL: Can I say these are my final values?
PAUL: On top of this, if you apply sorting, what will happen?
PAUL: On top of this sum of normalized squares, if you apply a simple sorting operation, I know that these are already sorted only in the first final few ranking fields only.
PAUL: Okay, so this is actually… your final results looks like.
PAUL: Alright, so in both the cases, I feel the calculations are pretty much simple, and anybody can tell the difference. If I say that, do you want to play with ranks, or do you want to play with scores?
PAUL: Now, a little bit difference, let's try to understand when I really try to do the differentiation, okay, between this, both the scenarios.
PAUL: Oh, sorry. RFS, I have written.
PAUL: Artific.
PAUL: Alright. Now, when I'm talking about… now, simply, those things, I won't be talking about scores and ranks. Okay, you guys already know that. One's work with schools, one work with ranks. In simple.
PAUL: Now, one of the most important things, if I'm talking about, where you feel, like, it's… the result is much more meaningful.
PAUL: In which process you feed?
PAUL: Quickly tell me.
PAUL: Because I want to get your idea also, where you feel that it's much more meaningful and reliable.
PAUL: Okay, now I'm getting missed results. Okay, now, simply, I will say that, okay, two important points.
PAUL: Best to win, okay?
PAUL: Now, that's why you have the situation here.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, when I'm, talking with respect to when you feel that somehow, okay, you are not getting very high scores.
PAUL: Okay? In that case, I feel that
PAUL: you should always go with RNF.
PAUL: When you have a full confidence, it means that on your solution, that my denser, sparse, everything is, like, up to the optimist level.
PAUL: scores that you were getting. In that case, use RS.
PAUL: Generally, I always do a testing in both the cases, okay, really, because directly, based on the implementation, I always feel that my scores are good. Okay, so I always do the testing, and I actually test it with always a subset of the data. Then I take my final decision.
PAUL: Now, one important thing is, like, if you have some type of outliers, then what? Okay, now here, little bit, the logic changes. If you have really outliers in your data.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to outliers, RRF, never use it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Always use.
PAUL: artist appointments.
PAUL: This is another thing.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: this is the… these two are the main one that I feel that… okay. Now, I feel that, really, with respect to schools, I feel that whenever I'm working with schools, I feel that I'm much more confident than with respect to ranks.
PAUL: So, my personal preference, as per my experimentations, I feel that RSF is better as compared to RSF.
PAUL: But majorly, everywhere in academics, they say RRF is better. So that's why I told you about the situation, where you should use one. Most of my personal use cases now, it really depends.
PAUL: Okay, like, which one? But always try to perform… to do the experiment directly, whether with respect to RRF, or whether with respect to RSF.
PAUL: If you are getting very high spores, and suddenly there is a very big drop based on that, how you can decide.
PAUL: Can you use judge scores? Yes, you can create a custom class through that if you want to take a judge scoring mechanism. That is also fine.
PAUL: JB, okay? So, yes, you can do an LLM as a judge scenario here also.
PAUL: Yes, according to academics, I feel that more focus is towards RF.
PAUL: Because it's easier. See, when something is much more simpler, it's accepted much more. But I feel that there is no such complexities in both algorithms. The other is very, very simple. At least in RSF, you need to do that mean-max normalization.
PAUL: So, only… but mean-max normalization, I feel, in the entire field of data science, everybody should be, combined, like, comfortable with that.
PAUL: When you see that, there is not a huge difference in… with respect to the schools. Cynthia.
PAUL: And somehow, we have to believe on the algorithm that you are working with.
PAUL: Now, if you use low-quality embedding models, then the entire game changes.
PAUL: Alright, these are a few of the scenarios, so my personal choice, when I say that, please use both, do the experiments.
PAUL: Okay, at least. And it's not like that there will be very, very huge difference in the results of R, R, F, and RSF. It's also nice that the percentage of difference generally comes around close to 3-7%.
PAUL: Okay, now it totally depends upon the quality of the data in my data, really simple. Like, it's not like 10-20% differences that comes. It doesn't happen in that way. Okay, because this is a scenario where you try to do merging. So, for sure, the comparison with respect to the results, it will be very, very least.
PAUL: If a document is having high schools, yes, in a dense source, that only PA works.
PAUL: It will have, for sure, higher rankers.
PAUL: Alright, now, this part I am done. Okay, I have shown you a Scratch implementation. Now you guys do the implementation of RSF and show.
PAUL: You can use Langchain or Llama Index. Do you want a boilerplate?
PAUL: If you want a boilerplate, I can even share Lama Index is much easier to do the implementation.
PAUL: But, a similar one, you can do it with respect to… by writing a custom function also. Because the mean map functions are available in a lot of places, so I want you guys to do the implementation.
PAUL: Just like me that I have done. Take your time, because I think within 10 to 15 minutes, you can do the implementation, and then we can.
PAUL: go ahead. Now, very similar implementation, you can take my last one. If you want some boilerplate, let me share some boilerplates,
PAUL: Because, really, I want you guys to do it every time, because, see, really with respect to the core implementation. If you remember, in Lama Intel, there was a Query Fusion Retriever. How many of you
PAUL: remember that. Okay, so I think I do have a toilet plate with me. So, for the Lama Intex I'm showing, okay, so simply, this is, the version. So, here you have this mode, mood is a relative score, which actually does RSF for you.
PAUL: Similarly, in Langchen, also.
PAUL: you can do it, but I want you guys to do at least a minimal
PAUL: implementation of that. So, LangChain everywhere, so these are directly available.
PAUL: Because in Langchen, there is no R, F… F. Support.
PAUL: I'll… I will repeat myself, always remember.
PAUL: our SF support is not there in Langchain. It means that you have to create a custom function.
PAUL: To do the implementation.
PAUL: Are in groups that are sorted with in RRF, if the documents are sorted with RRF ranking, then why does the size?
PAUL: We're different.
PAUL: REM, your question is only wrong. You're asking, docs are sorted with RF ranking. With RRF ranking, then why the dense and the sparse?
PAUL: Or… chance order a bit different.
PAUL: Now, the same question. Do you think that the result of the sparse and dense will always be equal?
PAUL: It is not possible.
PAUL: Okay, they will always have different results. So, when you ask then why the 10 cents path, what are different, it will always be different. I can never say that both of the ranks will be same.
PAUL: The scenario that you were telling, practically not possible.
PAUL: Now, the portion, Rishab Sharma is asking how to handle in case of multi-dimensional scores.
PAUL: Okay, multidimensional scores, what do you mean by that? I never heard about multidimensional scores, Rishan. Little bit, throw light.
PAUL: Okay, but we prefer dense. Dense is the most preferred one. Okay, it means that if your dense fails, then only you are… it's just like a fallback condition that you will be going ahead with sparse. Because sparse is pretty much exact keyword matching.
PAUL: So, first of all, we always look into the semantic. That's why I feel that the alpha value should be close to 0.55 or 0.6. Rest, whatever the value, you can put it for semantic.
PAUL: Howdy.
PAUL: Okay, so guys, please do the implementation and show me. Which implementation? You can do a scratch one. Okay, mean max normalization function is available through SQLAN, or write your own function in whichever way. Just remember, LangChain doesn't have any native support.
PAUL: Okay, if you want to do it langchen, I will be keep, sharing this particular information.
PAUL: Through a custom retriever, you have to create a custom function. Okay, so few boilerplates. Okay, so in Lansing, you have to create this particular custom RSF function, and through that, you have to do the implementation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, in whichever way, but at least show me, okay, take your time. I should not take… use AI, use ChatGPT, use anything. Take a sample, okay, or even ask. The same thing that I have done, do a complete copy-paste, and show me the implementation.
PAUL: Do the implementation of RRF, RR… sorry, RRF I have already done. Show me the implementation of RSF.
PAUL: Hi, this…
PAUL: This is a task, please do this task right now. It's not like after the class, I will do it.
PAUL: Alright, regarding RF, we need to validate my understanding. For a period, we got 10 chunks done. The… we done the embedding and save in vector store, correct? Based on the query, we retrieved the top 3 chunks from the vector data store, okay? How we make sure that all 3 chunks are same?
PAUL: How we make sure all three chunks are the same intense?
PAUL: Murakata, once you will have those chunks, okay, like, you will be applying your sparse embedding or, like, split on top of those chunks.
PAUL: It doesn't matter. Like, I'm not telling that for your PDF data, okay, like, for your chunk, you'll be applying a separate, algorithm, or basically the sparse vector that you'll be applying. It is on top of different data, on top of the same chunk only you apply.
PAUL: You were telling because both chunks can be different, yes, the rank of both chunks will be different, or can be different. Rarely, it will be in the same case.
PAUL: There is no direct support in Langchain. You have to create a custom function, and you have to pass it through a retriever. That's why that particular part I have shown.
PAUL: Alright, majorly this implementation, so take your time, do it, then probably we'll be going for a break.
PAUL: So, we got 3 chunks?
PAUL: See, Murta, 3 chunks you won't be getting. So, for example, on top of the entire data, you'll be applying your, embedding, whether it's sparse, whether it tells. On top of the entire data, I mean, on top of all the chunks. Then the ranking will happen.
PAUL: Alright, I think I can stop sharing.
PAUL: And always remember, like, don't think the output of the retriever is only 3 chunk, okay? You can get more by changing that top gate, always.
PAUL: Okay, now, okay, I think if you talk in that particular prospect… okay, let me just focus Murthaza's part little bit. Murta, as you were asking this part, let me just…
PAUL: tell this. Everybody is thinking that only document this one. Okay, now…
PAUL: For example, if you have 10 chunks.
PAUL: Okay, your question that you have. So, I will say C1, C2, C3, C4, something like this.
PAUL: Okay, and see fine. Now, simply, if I say with respect to the rank that I have.
PAUL: I'll be doing it for dance.
PAUL: Okay, and then I'll be doing it for sparse. Okay, now, in this particular result, in the tins, okay, so if I take, like, here, C3, in sparse, it can be C7 also.
PAUL: Because on top of the total chunks.
PAUL: That's… so don't think only you will be taking the 3 part. From here, what is the top 3? So here, C3 can come, again, your C9 can come, here your C5 can come, your C1 can come. This can differ, okay? Now, this ranking will always
PAUL: So, it can be a condition that, yes, C3 is available in both the top three parts.
PAUL: I hope I have made this part clear.
PAUL: Alright, now, Anirud is telling, sir, will this not increase the final response time? Really, like, these calculations doesn't take so much. It's not an LLM call, it's pretty much simple.
PAUL: Inversely.
PAUL: RSF support is by there. By default, Langchen works with RSF. That particular piece of code I have already shared with you. The default one is RSF only.
PAUL: Alright, Rajat, you have done okay, I will come and look into that.
PAUL: There is no support for R. RRF, by default, is supported in Langchain. RSF support is not there. And if you are getting very high scores, and certainly there is a big drop, we will choose RRF instead of ES.
PAUL: Score reliability also matters, that's why. Without language, can you use directly as can score? Haha, you can use. See, scratch formulas always hashes. It means that I have no issues. Really, like, I…
PAUL: For these type of implementations, you should always create some helper functions, and based on that, even I showed you some Scratch implementation, fine, it's not necessary you need to use LangChain
PAUL: How many of you think that for this implementation, you need Langchen and others? This is pure, simple math.
PAUL: Okay, so… 1037, take 5 to 10 minutes. Okay, and everybody, like, if you want a break, do your breakfast, so after probably 15 minutes, we will start back.
PAUL: So, let me look into that timer… okay, where is the clock?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Everybody, please do the implementation, so after the class, I'll be looking into it.
PAUL: reading books.
PAUL: Alright, guys, oh, I hope… Everyone is…
PAUL: Vara, I'll have looked into your code share, okay, that's correct only.
PAUL: Frank.
PAUL: What about others? Please let me know how many of you have… I'm done.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: What about others? Only 3 people told none.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Fine, so I think…
PAUL: I don't always remember with respect to RRF or with respect to RSF, okay, so whenever you are doing the retrieval, don't pull only 3, okay? At least pull 5, at least pull 10 different documents.
PAUL: The top K should be a higher number, it should not be 3.
PAUL: Always remember that.
PAUL: the result of the fusion will be better if you have more top K.
PAUL: Alright, I think we can move to the next part.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I think everyone is back, please let me know, so that we can continue the next part.
PAUL: alert, so…
PAUL: So, we'll take the average of the scores for each chunk if we take more than one retriever. Every time it will be more than one retriever only.
PAUL: Not to laugh.
PAUL: It… there can be… Like, 2 Retriever, even 3 Retriever.
PAUL: Because multivector till now, like, is not in your syllabus, but I will cover it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so I think I can start sharing my screen.
PAUL: Abhijit, I think, could we always use the concept of hybrid searches a safe… Mechanically.
PAUL: The idea is not to be dependent on only one retriever. Okay, so that's why I feel that it's fine.
PAUL: Alright guys, now, a little bit will we start talking with respect to lay ranking.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: I think, with respect to re-ranking, you already have the notebook.
PAUL: Okay, so before that, let's try to understand exactly, like.
PAUL: What is re-ranking, and how it is referred to as a second pass filter.
PAUL: Alright, so the notebook is already there, so I think we can start our… nautical discussion.
PAUL: Let me just open my notes, and then we will continue.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all… will be.
PAUL: Right now, talking with respect to re-ranking.
PAUL: Okay, so… I will use the term re-ranker.
PAUL: Okay, so little concepts will come from your transformers here, because transformers are very, very important.
PAUL: The fundamentals of transformers comes into the picture here, directly.
PAUL: So the, first thing, before rewriting.
PAUL: So, right now, can I say that I have done some type of ranking here also?
PAUL: In hybrid search, how many of you think that we have done some type of ranking here?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: And very specifically with respect to, RRF, if I'm talking about.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Okay, so the things with respect to our…
PAUL: hybrid search that I have done.
PAUL: I have done a semantic search, as well as a full text search, okay, so both sparse and dense vectors, that comes into the picture.
PAUL: Now, there is one bottleneck, and that bottleneck I want…
PAUL: everybody, to understand, okay? Now, just think about whenever you are performing embedding.
PAUL: So, embeddings are what type of model?
PAUL: any type of embedding model. So, what type of model are referred to as embedding models, guys?
PAUL: According to Transformers.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, don't say Transformers according to Transformers Architecture.
PAUL: Alright, encoders, correct, correct. People are telling encoders, but what type of encoders?
PAUL: There are multiple types of encoders also. I'll be just telling text, no, not text.
PAUL: That's why here, the fundamental things lies with respect to the fundamental architecture. Majorly, all of the, embedding models that you have, like, most of them, not all, I will use the term, rather than I will use the most one. They are bi-importers.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So… And why I've taken this particular embedding model.
PAUL: For now. Because little bit, most of the embedding models, are based on… buy encoders.
PAUL: Now… The question comes. If you have something as a buy encoder.
PAUL: Okay, so let's take you have two things.
PAUL: query?
PAUL: And I will say context.
PAUL: Can I say that on top of these two, I do apply embedding.
PAUL: directly.
PAUL: Please tell me.
PAUL: Are there any relations?
PAUL: Can I say that? They include the query and the documents. Documents, I am referring as context, okay? So, you can think about context or documents, because in this class, we are referring chunks as documents.
PAUL: Can I?
PAUL: Say that they are encoded separately?
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: So, in simple terms, when you are using by encoders, okay, they do the encoding of the query and the document separately. Now, this leads to problem.
PAUL: Okay, so one of a few of the major problems, if I talk about, one is it will hamper your precision.
PAUL: Okay, so what are the problems that you have?
PAUL: Okay, and always remember that embedding models
PAUL: I'm buying quotas. Okay. Because,
PAUL: not a single person in this class told me, because that's why that… a little bit with respect to transformer's part is important, but…
PAUL: It's in-depth. Actually, when we deal with LLMs much more transformers architecture, then we talk about this.
PAUL: Now, the first problem, if you are encoding something, okay, so they will have lesser precision.
PAUL: Always remember that, okay?
PAUL: And the other problem is… missing.
PAUL: context.
PAUL: Can I say this? These two are genuine problems, yes on.
PAUL: Okay, now this is why we will try to bring re-rankers.
PAUL: Okay, now this is a mean reason. If somebody asks you why relancers comes into the picture, Okay.
PAUL: So, when I use the term, why? Always remember, you have to tell these two points, because they are by encoders, and they encode the query and the document separately, which leads to problems like lesser precision, and sometimes even missing,
PAUL: context also.
PAUL: Now, what are re-rankers in simple terms?
PAUL: Okay, so read anchors are cross-encoders.
PAUL: What is a cross-encoder?
PAUL: When I say, what is a cross encoder in simple terms?
PAUL: No idea. All right.
PAUL: Now, here, there was a missing link. It means that both the things were different. Now, think about, can we
PAUL: do the combination of both. It means that a joint encoding operation.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: the joint in… This is re-ranking, yes, re-ranker and re-ranking. You do re-ranking using re-rankers, Borgave, okay?
PAUL: Generate embedding by seeing the query redox.
PAUL: Alright, now, the idea is to do this joint encoding mechanism. It means that
PAUL: Whenever, these, I can say, cross-encoders will be using, I will jointly encode the query and the document together.
PAUL: Okay, so… Join encoding op.
PAUL: query.
PAUL: And… your dock.
PAUL: Together.
PAUL: Now, what is the benefit of this?
PAUL: Can I say that if you do a joint encoding operation, they will… they will help you to capture deeper relationship and context?
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: See, guys, I'm just going through the fundamentals right now. It's pretty much fundamentals.
PAUL: Now, Anirud is asking, sir, it is encoding or embedding. Embedding is encoding.
PAUL: There is no OR. Embedding is encoding.
PAUL: Okay? Alright, I will repeat the last.
PAUL: Till this point, it's clear for everyone what is the idea and why we are trying to do a join encoding operation. Take one class for… one class transform is not possible. If I teach transformers, it will take two to three months.
PAUL: Because in Transformers, it's really in-depth, so that's why even we don't launch patches just to teach
PAUL: Transformers… because, see, this… if I teach transformers, it will be only the core one. But on top of transformers, in the last 3 years, what has happened, those are totally different things. Alright. Now, the idea is that we'll perform a joint encoding. So, joint encoding will help me to capture
PAUL: Deeper.
PAUL: relationship.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: And context also.
PAUL: This is the core purpose, because during your retrieval, okay, the query is encoded in one form, the document is encoded. Now, the idea is, let's try to do the…
PAUL: combination. So, generally, what happens, the cross encoder will apply the core fundamental technique of transformers, which is referred to as
PAUL: self-attention, okay?
PAUL: This is where self-attention comes into the picture.
PAUL: Okay, so cross encoders will apply self-attention
PAUL: Okay, and I think everybody knows, self-attention is a mechanism in transformer's model.
PAUL: that give weightage importance to different type of words in simple terms, okay? Based on the input relative to each other. Right now, I'm not teaching you self-attention, I'm just telling you, yes, through this, we actually do it.
PAUL: Now, with respect to self-attention, I know that this particular process will actually help me to enable the model to focus on the most relevant words in the context. Now, this is all related with respect to self-potential. I don't want to go in that depth, but this is the core fundamental thing.
PAUL: And this is what, even in Transformers, that comes into the picture.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now the question comes… Because of this.
PAUL: re-rankers always get a better, I can say, context with respect to the user's query or the user's intent.
PAUL: In relationship with the documents context.
PAUL: Because of this operation, in simple terms, two things that happens. Rahid anchors, Get two things.
PAUL: One, it will get the, query intent.
PAUL: Okay, the intent of the query, with the relationship, Of the document context.
PAUL: Alright, now this is the main purpose of doing re-ranking.
PAUL: But, you have to understand re-rankers, any type of re-ranking that you want to apply.
PAUL: This is a computationally expensive task.
PAUL: This is… it means that
PAUL: I always don't prefer to use re-ranking. Okay, it means that it will always come with the time, because at the end of the day, you are bringing cross encoders into the system, and cross-encoders are expensive models. It means that it takes much more added time.
PAUL: Okay. Now, using cross encoders, now I will try to generate, okay? Now, but docs have been encoded and saved in Vector Store, that is fine.
PAUL: That is fine, Motada. There is no issue in that, because that is a default way. You'll always do that particular encoding operation. But the relationship is not there. Now, the idea is how to make that relationship. That relationship, we will try to make it using cross inputers.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, generally, rank… always remember, re-ranking can also be done with respect to LLMs also. You can ask LLM to do a re-ranking operation. It is not necessary that every time you have to use a cross-end quarter, okay? So, little bit with respect to re-ranker types also, I will say.
PAUL: Okay, so one is the cross encoder. This is the most widely used one.
PAUL: Okay, LLM also, so LLM ranker, you read anchor also, you can use it.
PAUL: LLM re-anchor means you will ask the LLM to do that for you.
PAUL: Narula is asking, a strange question, you have. Is this done with cross-quarters or with separate encoders? Cross encoders. I've used the term cross encoders, why? Here, so many times.
PAUL: Okay, I have not written cross encoder. Okay, alright, let me write cross-encoder, otherwise you guys will forget.
PAUL: Major League re-ranking will be… you guys will be doing the implementation, and I want to focus on cross-encoders much more, don't focus on LLM re-ranking operation, because again, through a prompt, it will do that inject operation, and it will ask the LLM. I don't feel that…
PAUL: Because that, again, becomes a much more costly operation.
PAUL: Okay, now, generally, most of the embedding models, okay, it will… it has a certain formula. For example, if I take open embedding text 3 small, okay, so based on that formula, it will be, do the computation, okay, of your embeddings, and it will store it.
PAUL: Now, re-rankers, what we'll do. ReLranker will process the each query document pair. Always re- remember this cross-encoder.
PAUL: Okay, this re-ranking, it will always process in this format.
PAUL: In the pair of Q and D. Q and D, Q refers to the query, and D refers to the document pair. Okay. Through the ranking model, during the query time, it means that during inferencing, it is used.
PAUL: Okay, during… inferencing.
PAUL: Okay, it means that during your prediction in simple terms, you will be using this.
PAUL: Now, the question comes, computationally expensive task when I'm talking about, it means that the cross-encoding, every query document pair, when you really, think about, this is a computational burden also. Okay, it means that
PAUL: And this is quadratic in nature, and sometimes if I say, so computationally, this is very, very expensive. Okay, and the response of the, original rack system will be toward the lower side. It means that till hybrid search, you will see that you got in the result probably, let's take, like, within 20 seconds you got.
PAUL: But once you break rear anchors, probably 10 more seconds, that might get added. Because here, there are different type of rear anchor models.
PAUL: You can pick something in between, and generally the preference, whenever you are working with re-rankers, you always prefer to use a good one. Because if you use something, a bad re-ranking model, then again, if you get something good result from your hybrid search, then also it will be impacted.
PAUL: Okay, so somehow I feel that at least if you're going ahead with the re-rankers.
PAUL: So I will be showing you a few good versions, and majorly the, most famous ones come from Kohar.
PAUL: That's why they are completely paid. Okay, you have to use their APIs to use them.
PAUL: Okay, so always remember, like, very, very expansion task. Now, I will come to that particular step. So.
PAUL: The first thing is the two-stage retrieval.
PAUL: Because real advers are referred to as a two-stage retrieval part.
PAUL: In the last class, with respect to split also, like, one-stage retrieval systems and two-stage retrieval systems, so re-rankers always fall in that category.
PAUL: A two-stage retrieval system.
PAUL: hybrid such, if you're just only working with hybrid such, then I can say that yes.
PAUL: On top of…
PAUL: I can say that is at least a single stage retrieval that you were doing, but once you do array ranking, it means that another operation on top of your search results. So generally, like, why do stage? So, once you have the vector search results, okay.
PAUL: On top of that, you will be applying.
PAUL: On top of your vector search results.
PAUL: You will be applying re-ranking.
PAUL: Okay, and after that, the rank documents order can be different, so always remember that if there was a certain order, like document A, B, C, D, after re-ranking, probably document D might be toward the higher side. So, it actually depends upon the query.
PAUL: And even with respect to the query also, so I told you, like, if you… in the relanking, also you have good models and bad models.
PAUL: Length of the query matters. This is a very important factor.
PAUL: Weak models cannot handle it, actually. Length of the query.
PAUL: In any type of rank, can I say that there will be a length of the query?
PAUL: It means that if your query is very, very long and very, very complex, in that case, really, the weak lead rank anchors generally doesn't work out very good. Okay, so in those cases, you really need good ones.
PAUL: Okay, now, by default, always remember that the problem that I have told you here, okay, lesser precision. So, by default, any type of rack that you are building, and just think about you are not using re-ranking, a simple, retrieval system that you have built.
PAUL: that retrieval system will be focusing on which metric a lot. Can anybody tell me?
PAUL: the default rack system.
PAUL: I'm not using re-rankers, forget about it. Just think about the name rack for now.
PAUL: Which metric it actually focuses much more.
PAUL: Okay, always remember, that is your recall.
PAUL: Only the major metric that it focuses on. Other metrics are not actually focused, okay? So, the major focus is…
PAUL: On the recall, through the context window.
PAUL: Now, the idea is that somehow we need to improve our precision, okay? Now, re-rankers will actually help you to increase your precision of your rank system.
PAUL: Okay, whereas, like, I cannot see a lot of focus towards the recall that is actually put.
PAUL: Nope.
PAUL: in your entire system till now, how things will work. So, now the second stage ranking, as I'm telling, like, two-stage retrieval. So, simply, like, second stage, ranking pipelines, exactly how it… your flow will look like. So, first of all, with respect to your query, I will just try to draw a simple…
PAUL: Diagram here, okay, query.
PAUL: Okay, and the first thing is your process documents.
PAUL: Okay, process documents… That I'll be passing it to Ven.
PAUL: embedding model.
PAUL: For now, this is a simple block that I have drawn.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, the same embedding model, if I am, doing it, okay?
PAUL: There will be your VS, your vector store.
PAUL: Yes, this is the float.
PAUL: From your vector store, you'll be getting the retrib docs.
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: Now, on top of this retrieve docs. Okay, now, I'm taking a simple retriever only, let's take it, not necessary. So, this retrieve docs can be the output of the hybrid search, or the output without the hybrid search. Simple, dense search also.
PAUL: Now, on top of this, I'll be applying Europe?
PAUL: The re-ranking number.
PAUL: Alright, now, from the relanking, what will happen?
PAUL: this… Docs, whatever that came. Okay, so in simple terms…
PAUL: You'll be getting your ranked documents.
PAUL: That we call the final output. Okay, and now this will be actually sent to the… LLM?
PAUL: For your response generation, and finally, you'll be getting your response.
PAUL: So, a simple added module, and this is a plug-and-play module.
PAUL: But really, it comes with a cost rise. So that's why it is referred to as that second stage ranking. Okay, or generally, it comes under that two-stage retrieval systems.
PAUL: Now, the question comes, how to select a read anchor model.
PAUL: the selection procedure?
PAUL: So, most of the times, whenever you are doing a re-ragging, please don't retrieve only 3 documents.
PAUL: Okay, the retrieval should be at least of higher number.
PAUL: Most of the cases, even in hybrid search also, I've told you, use bigger numbers, 10, 20, 30. Okay, in production, you will see, like, it is always close to 50, 40, 60, these are the common numbers that we play with.
PAUL: RSF or RRF can be used? Yes, RF… see, entire thing of RRF and RSF comes in this part.
PAUL: R, F?
PAUL: or RSA.
PAUL: Okay, it comes in this part.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: That is the recturing docs, in simple terms. On top of the return docs, whatever you want to apply, you want to apply RF, RSF, anything.
PAUL: Alright. Now, on top of the results of hybrid search, you will be applying your rewriting.
PAUL: Okay, if you apply hybrid search, if you don't apply hybrid search, on top of both the results, simply you can pass.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Yes, so we passed the RDocs and the query both to the crafts and coder, yes.
PAUL: But actually, don't think about the original form, it's much more about the embedding form that is getting
PAUL: Available there.
PAUL: Alright, now, always remember in every time, the top K documents should be of higher number, okay? So, something around 50.
PAUL: This is, like, production standards. So, 3 and 4, we don't play with these type of tasks.
PAUL: Now, generally, on top of this 50, okay, and this 50 can reach till 1000, candidly, totally depends upon
PAUL: that particular result, how much or big is your data? So it… after re-ranking, you can say that, okay.
PAUL: from this 50 or 1,000, I need only the top 20 to 25.
PAUL: Okay, so here we'll be just ensuring that after re-ranking, we'll be getting the most relevant documents.
PAUL: Okay, now this is always considered. So, this is basically a refinement.
PAUL: On top of your… Retrieve results.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why a refinement procedure, that happens.
PAUL: Now, relanch our model sizes, so generally, higher models, okay, are… will be better. Always remember that the models which are bigger in size, okay, with higher number of parameters, they will be, like, better. It means that you will be getting higher accuracy.
PAUL: Why a higher accuracy? Bigger models?
PAUL: See, bigger… Reed anchors.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Will always have high accuracy.
PAUL: When I say the term accuracy, simply, don't think about a machine learning metric. The idea is that it means that it will be capturing much more deeper semantic relationship.
PAUL: That is the meaning of accuracy that I am referring here, so don't get confused.
PAUL: But… The latency will be high.
PAUL: Always remember, latency will be towards the higher side, because that's why computational cost also it comes.
PAUL: So you have to always select it between, like, which one is the best.
PAUL: Okay. Now, one simple example with respect to shorter queries and complex queries, if I'm talking about. I think sometime in this particular batch, I told about VuaJai.
PAUL: Okay, they are the, I can say, the market leaders in re-rankers, really. Like, they have good, re-ranking models.
PAUL: Now, generally for shorter queries and longer queries, a simple example with respect to GoaJI data will take, okay, short query…
PAUL: And long query, I've told you.
PAUL: The length of the query affects your re-ranking model.
PAUL: So, generally, for short queries, there is a re-rank to Lite version, which is available in Voa JI.
PAUL: Okay, now these are a few models.
PAUL: I'll be talking about open source models also now, but these are paid models.
PAUL: And then you have that, re-rank to light.
PAUL: And only you have that re-rank.
PAUL: Voyage model, okay.
PAUL: this is 2, and this is too light. That is the only difference. So generally, for longer queries, we generally suggest in production systems, if you really want to go ahead, okay, rather than just picking any random thing, you can pick something from Hugging Face, really, like,
PAUL: it doesn't work so much. I have tested it in part. Sometimes it works, sometimes it really doesn't work, but the results with Kohar and Vouch, all the paid things are really up to the mark. I've seen, like, real changes, but with respect to the open source weights.
PAUL: Very few models are there that I'll be talking about probably in next month with respect to unified embedding concept. Okay, so few models are there, but again, they are exp… it means that you cannot run them on CPU. For them, you need a VRAM. So, again, those solutions becomes out of our context.
PAUL: And the other thing that matters, can anybody tell me? Here I told the length of the query, so what is the other factor that can affect the re-ranker?
PAUL: What is the other factor that can affect?
PAUL: Noise, no, no, no. Noise, no. What are the input to the re-ranker, guys? Chunk size, correct equation. I was looking for chunk size.
PAUL: Document size, also, you can search, or chunk size. That also plays a crucial role.
PAUL: So, always remember that, that two things here comes, because Q and D, so if your queue is somehow short and long, it, like, plays, a crucial factor with respect to the output of your, Ridge Anchor, similarly, the chunk size in the vector database.
PAUL: Okay? So generally, you should have larger chunk sites. You should not go with small chunk size. Always remember, larger is better in this particular case.
PAUL: So, this is a simple selection, okay, based on what? So, I will write that chum size pattern also. So, with respect to chum size, it should not be very small.
PAUL: Chunk size of 1000 is good.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Okay, so somewhere between 800 to 2000 works really good.
PAUL: Okay, so I feel that re-ranker is just a plug-and-play module, you should keep it. It's not like that every system needs it.
PAUL: Because here, a lot of things comes into the picture, because though it helps you to do a lot of balancing factors, like, somewhere with respect to accuracy, but again, the latency, again, the computational resources, so that's why few concerns are there.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, always start with opting with a lightweight model, because if you have some type of query, later on, at least, we know that we can do some type of query transformation. Okay, it means that through some transformation, based on certain characters, I can put some logic, and actually I can do it.
PAUL: Because if you actually get bigger models, the latency will be very high. But for sure, the result will be much better.
PAUL: Alright, now, this was all about…
PAUL: our re-ranking process, step-by-step, everything that I approved. Now, we'll be going through our core implementation.
PAUL: I have given you the fundamental logic with respect to transformers and exactly what it happens.
PAUL: No, the dimension of the embedding doesn't matter.
PAUL: Alright guys, so let's start.
PAUL: Yes, Abhisheikh, re-ranking is gone on top of the retrieved chunks, correct?
PAUL: Anirud is asking, 30 seconds for a rack response without streaming. Is it acceptable? Yes, it is.
PAUL: It depends upon the LLM also, no? Unirot, if you are using, actually, a very good LLM.
PAUL: Okay, probably with respect to, reasonable model, reasoning model. For sure, it will take time. There is no problem with that.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just now start going through the notebook.
PAUL: Because with respect to, read anchors, the fundamental things.
PAUL: I have, already told you.
PAUL: Now, coming to this. Now, do you want me to go much more with respect to token-level stuff?
PAUL: Because that part… It's also there, but generally.
PAUL: It's only for masters, like, post-grad and PhD students only, I feel it is required.
PAUL: Okay, so leave that part. Majority of people are telling no, fine.
PAUL: Because actually, token level settings are a little bit different.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with our practical implementations.
PAUL: Ravan, what is pricing?
PAUL: Alright, so I think today Meng should come with respect to sharing coupons for the platform.
PAUL: Alright, I think probably after the session, he might come.
PAUL: Because the platform is ready, so that Evolveview platform with our initial early bird testers, we'll be providing you at least one month of pro access to all the students.
PAUL: I think this is my dexter of 3, this is my core one, yes.
PAUL: Everybody plays open your notebook.
PAUL: Because, when I say a joint encoding operation, so people who understand transformers, okay, always think that tokens will come, that classification token, CLS, okay?
PAUL: and separated two things. So, that is how you do the separation between your query and your QTalk. That was the thing that I was telling, in high level, if I was talking about.
PAUL: What is open source, we can use for eRanker? There are open source models, majorly the MS Marco.
PAUL: Widely used. Everyone for learning, they use it.
PAUL: Modas already asking, are there any good online learning sites that give sandbox for performing this exercise online? I'm not sure about that.
PAUL: Really, like, I don't do these operations. Generally, I take a GPU for 1 month, 2 months, 1 year, on those hardware right of it.
PAUL: All right, guys, so let's start with our, core implementation. The same things with respect to a few other things that I have mentioned. So, everybody please check, because this is a pure lanction-based implementation. So, have a check that everything with respect to the first import section is working, because everything is…
PAUL: I will say standard. Only one new import that you might feel, which is the cross encoder.
PAUL: Through this, I'll be actually calling the Hugging Face model.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, for re-ranking, GPU is not necessary, but for good re-ranking models, you need your GPU.
PAUL: No Aruna. That's not part… Here.
PAUL: Okay, so you have, like, low-resizing models I'll be using, don't worry. There is always open source alternate.
PAUL: And, really, like, that's why Kohar actually become famous. I feel that people use less their LLMs and more their re-rankers.
PAUL: in production.
PAUL: Though they provide multiple models, embedding models are also there, but I feel somehow that is…
PAUL: my version of Kohler, it means that for major… mostly, like, for past 1-2 year solutions, Kohar LLM might never pick up their LLMs. I pick up LLMs from the Anthropic family. I don't use…
PAUL: OpenAI a lot. Complete suits are built on Anthropic only.
PAUL: And majorly through AWS, that's why I work with AWS much more.
PAUL: RT40, 50 is enough for re-ranking years, I think.
PAUL: Most of the times, you need at least a 6GB VRAM. Okay, so always remember 6GB VRAM till it goes around 16GB.
PAUL: Alright guys, please have a check, and then let me know all the imports are working successfully or not.
PAUL: Everybody… Please execute the notebook, and then let me know.
PAUL: Working? Alright.
PAUL: Fine, let's take our, document path?
PAUL: Then comes PDF encoding.
PAUL: Okay, so, LLM-based function to rank…
PAUL: Now, this particular option is an LLM ranker. I told you there are two types of rankers. You can do re-ranking using LLM, so this is one approach.
PAUL: Where, through a particular template, on a scale of 1 to 10, rate the relevance of the following document to the query. Okay, now, really, I don't want to focus on… a lot on this approach, because again, this comes with a cost, as you know, again, an LLM call will be made. But yes, you'll be getting your final results.
PAUL: So this is one way of implementing your LLM Ranker. I think Langchain does not have a native support for LLM Ranker, whereas
PAUL: Lama Indecdazakh.
PAUL: Now, from here, I will be simply passing a query. You can see, right here, with respect to my similarity search, the retriever. Okay, and then finally, I am applying re-ranking. And right here, K is equal to 15, the initial docs that I am passing. So, can you see query with the set of docs that I am passing, guys?
PAUL: query with the set of docs, the same formula that I wrote, Q comma T.
PAUL: Okay, so now let's try to do the execution from here. Now, this is a LLM-based ranker.
PAUL: But then I will come to the, main implementation.
PAUL: As this is through an LLM, so it will take some time, so just wait.
PAUL: Okay, so based on the query, what are the impacts of climate change on biodiversity? So, climate change is alternating terrestrial ecosystems.
PAUL: Okay, top initial documents that you have.
PAUL: Okay? These are the initial documents, guys, and after that ranking has been done, okay, and you can see simply the change with respect to the documents. This time, the rerun document, climate change is alternating, so if you really look into
PAUL: this document and this document, after rewriting, can I say that both the chunks are the same?
PAUL: So, this can also happen. This is pretty much common. It means that the result of your hybrid search is really good.
PAUL: So that's why I feel that Reaction is an optional module, it's not a compulsion module, always remember that.
PAUL: Okay, then,
PAUL: The next thing with respect to document, too, if you really look into here, some things, policy should promote synergies between climate, okay, now this part.
PAUL: Yeah, so the document, too, has changed. So, really, like, based on the impact, like, what are the impacts of climate change on biodiversity? I feel that this one, because here are some health impacts, heat-related illness, rising temperatures.
PAUL: few things that has been mentioned here. But again, when I look into the re-rank documents here, pural rips are highly sensitive to changes, okay, and now this is a real problem.
PAUL: of climate change.
PAUL: So, the term which is referred to as, like, coral beaching, which take place. Okay, so I feel that, yes, this is much better summer.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And here, a few things are mentioned. Again, if you look into Document 3, what are the effects of climate change? There's hurricanes, I believe, heat waves, I believe, droughts, again, heavy rainfall. Yes, that is also correct here.
PAUL: And here, if you look into document 3, climate resiliation, conservation, so this part, when I feel that.
PAUL: identifying climate, and even I have not printed out the entire one, but somehow I feel that this one is much lesser relevant. So, first two in this case are much better.
PAUL: Here, I feel that 1 and 3 is similar to the better, but yes, the impacts are there. Because right now, simply, I'm talking with respect to the impacts, it can be any impact, so in document to health impacts.
PAUL: heart-related and other things. So, in the real world, if I say that, I feel that the result of our initial document is actually good. It's not very bad.
PAUL: Yes, probably a few things might get changed, and we can do the improvement by how?
PAUL: I told you, always use.
PAUL: high top K chunks. Right now, I've taken the example of 3. If you actually try to pull up and try to get a bigger, top K chunk, make K is equal to, like, 15 or 20. For sure, you will be getting better ones.
PAUL: Paul, in this react, it will be using our
PAUL: RF or RSF. Where is RRF or RSF? Right now, I told you. This is pure LLM.
PAUL: This is LLM re-ranking that we have done. Is this part clear for everyone? Please let me know. First, I have taken an example with respect to LLM.
PAUL: Then I will come to your Sentence Transformers implementation.
PAUL: Guys, please let me know. Take your time, take 2 minutes, go through the notebook. I don't feel that, it's very tough.
PAUL: Please analyze the results.
PAUL: Rishav is asking, do in such cases, does it make sense to just use re-ranker and not embedding model? Rishav, embedding model you will be using every point of time, but re-ranking is an optional. I cannot say embedding model is an optional to you.
PAUL: Embedding model is a must, or a compulsion, you cannot leave the embedding model.
PAUL: But you can leave out reading, okay?
PAUL: Please, guys, let me know in the chat, is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: Everybody is silent in chat. What happened?
PAUL: I think this implementation is easy, only it's not tough, please let me know, because purely with respect to the practical, the LLM ranking is really, really easy. There is nothing…
PAUL: It's tough here. It's pure lunching.
PAUL: And really, not tough lunch, and I can say easy lunch.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Alright, now I will move to the next part.
PAUL: Yes, that can also happen, Abhishek, like, yes, for sure. You might feel that the results of the hybrid search, okay, or the simple, then search only I'm taking for now.
PAUL: They can be seen.
PAUL: Okay, it means that the output… this is a very common case in read anchors.
PAUL: Okay, but I feel that… If the query is complex, then the game-changing thing happens.
PAUL: Okay, if the query is complex, your rack, might fail.
PAUL: That's why for complex queries, generally, re-rankers are much more better. Or you have to do some type of query transformation technique. Through that you need to hand. I told you two things matter for re-rankers. One is that chunk size and the query size.
PAUL: So, if it is very, very small.
PAUL: I feel that if it is very small, somehow then search can do that, but if it becomes bigger, somehow I feel that then the embedding that is getting generated, that there is that lesser relationship.
PAUL: So, for those complex queries, I feel that, yes, re-racking is a good approach.
PAUL: Generally, I've seen a production system, they'll directly apply. If the user has passed a query of, like, 100 characters, or 150 characters, directly they move into. By default, they will apply redirectly.
PAUL: Based on that particular logic. So, for complex queries, generally, it's good, but again, we take that complex query, then we will do our transformation, then on top of that, rewrite. Okay, so step-by-step, multiple things that comes into the picture.
PAUL: Nitesh is asking, GPT-40 is a re-anchor model. How many of you think GPT-40 is a re-ranker model? Nitesh, when you are asking this question, GPT-40 is a LLM.
PAUL: Alright, now, this is a custom retriever implementation that I have done it, so… really, you can do that way or this way, because in Langshan, I don't think there is a native support directly for LLM ranking, but in Llama Index, it is available.
PAUL: Okay? Now,
PAUL: Here, as you can see, written the re-ranked documents previously. Okay, so if I show you, actually, now, this particular function only, I'm actually calling.
PAUL: So, through this, I'm making a retrieval.
PAUL: Okay, now this is a simple implementation.
PAUL: So, you can think about 3 levels of retrieval that you can do, like, in your ensemble retriever, in your line chain. First, the sparse retriever, then comes your dense retriever, then finally comes this one, a rank retriever. So, this is a simple example. If you want, you can take this as a retriever-based implementation also.
PAUL: Alright, now… No, I think I've… Not sharing with respect to… Dope.
PAUL: Now, really, the focus on… This part, I think…
PAUL: We'll be moving ahead. Now, it totally depends, like, you want to go with the nave version with the custom retriever, because both of the things serves the same logic. There is no difference with respect to the logic.
PAUL: Now, I think we'll be talking with respect to our…
PAUL: Heritable searches a little bit. The method 2, I feel, the crossing borders.
PAUL: Everybody, please focus on this part of the cross-emoters models. Can you see here, I've defined here MS Marco?
PAUL: mini LM modules.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, simply, if you do a web search for this one, okay?
PAUL: So, where is my version? Okay, so let me just get it.
PAUL: So, this is MS Marco Mini LM L6 V2 version.
PAUL: Okay, now, this is a re-racking model.
PAUL: And directly, as you can see from Center's transformers, you can actually import it, and then you can pass it. Can you see here? This is a query.
PAUL: And this is a dock.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a pure re-ranker model that I am using this time.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now, the idea is you can do an implementation through transformers, through sentence transformers. I feel the sentence transformers is much more easier, so you can stick to the sentence transformer implementation.
PAUL: Alright, so let's get back. Okay, I think why I've kept this part, I want to just have a loop once.
PAUL: Okay, that demonstrates why we should use re-ranking. Okay, this was actually an example with respect to comparing the RAT techniques as compared to the…
PAUL: Simple retriever with the relanged version. That's it.
PAUL: Alright, now this is not so important, you can skip this set, okay? So this is a simple baseline retrieval with three ranker and without this one. So here you can see I'm… I am just calling my custom retriever. So, based on that, if you really want to have a check.
PAUL: So, from here, you get that, okay, base one. What is the capital of France? In the result, the capital of France is great, and the capital of France is beautiful.
PAUL: Okay? In the advanced retrieval, have you ever visited Paris? It is a beautiful city. Can you see here, what is the effect?
PAUL: of re-ranking.
PAUL: I want to show you this effect. When you actually ask your query, what is the capital of France? Actually, you will be getting for sure the capital of France.
PAUL: Just because of this scheme. Just because of this scheme. Because it is unable to capture deeper context.
PAUL: And this example justifies why Kept it here.
PAUL: I hope everybody understands that, where your normal death search might fail.
PAUL: How many of you got this particular example? Please let me know.
PAUL: Naga, please solve module not found error, okay? Because don't ask me module not found error at this point of time.
PAUL: Okay, how many of you get it? Mitesh is asking, please explain it. What is there to explain? Just try to analyze. I have passed a query, what is the capital of France? So, in simple terms, what should be the answer?
PAUL: generally, I know that this is a generic query. If it goes to the LLM, even the retrieve doc doesn't matter to us. The LLM will throw me the correct answer. But I'm showing you with respect to the retrieve docs. When you look into the top two docs, do you think that are you getting some type of answer?
PAUL: My answer is Paris. Is it there in the retrieved documents?
PAUL: It's not there.
PAUL: But with respect to applying redirecting, okay, so somehow I feel that, have you ever visited Paris? It's a beautiful city. And other things with respect to Paris that I'm getting the notice. This was the core part.
PAUL: Alright, now, method 2. Okay, now method 2, so here, I will be creating a, again, a cross-encoder retriever class. Okay, so this is, again, a custom implementation class. So, directly, I think, if you want, you can take that example also from here, I think.
PAUL: This one, and you can copy-paste it here.
PAUL: Take this entire thing, I should… it would work, there should not be any issues.
PAUL: Yeah, so let me just comment it out, and it will be getting some scores, okay?
PAUL: This is just a check that everything is working or not. Can you see right now, the model is getting downloaded?
PAUL: the real anchor model from Hugging Face.
PAUL: Okay, I'm… finally, I'm getting that joint encoding score here.
PAUL: Alright, so I know that this is working, so next time it won't be asking me to do a downloading of this one.
PAUL: So here, I created as a custom cross-emporter class. Just remember, I will just change that re-ranking function. I won't be using a re-ranking, rather than
PAUL: Directly, the output of the cross and border will help me to detect that.
PAUL: So, can you see here? So, most of the things here with respect to this definition. So, right here, few initializations, that are required, the vector store, the cross and border, then few other things with respect to Pyrentic that I have defined as required to define a custom retriever and line chain.
PAUL: Now, get relevant documents. Okay, now this is how the base retriever definition that needs to be taken if you are actually building your custom. So here, first of all, we are looking into the initial docs.
PAUL: So, what is this operation it will do?
PAUL: Tell me, guys, what this operation will do.
PAUL: When you look into this line of code, it is what it is doing.
PAUL: A simple search.
PAUL: From there, I'll be getting my initial docs. Now, on top of that, what I'm doing, first, I have to create the
PAUL: query document pair. So, this is where I'm actually performing the query document pair through our initial docs, actually. Okay, so because here, the core one is initial docs, so all of the docs from the result that I am applying.
PAUL: Now, I have this, my pair ready, of Q and D, that I'll be passing it to the encoder for prediction.
PAUL: From there, I'll be getting the encoder scores. Then, we will sort the documents by the scores, and finally, we will return the top, the rank results. Okay?
PAUL: So, let me execute this.
PAUL: Nage is telling cross-attention code. No, no, no, no, cross encoder. There is no cross-attention.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, as the custom retriever is available in the next case, simply, I can define the retriever through an initialization, and then I can actually pass it in the chain.
PAUL: Okay, so that's the core objective, because the rest of the code actually remains the same.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the, chain version, I think, and from there, if you really looked into
PAUL: like, the final result that I'm getting, because I think I'm printing out the top K. I think somewhere I've defined K is equal to 5. As you can see, K is equal to 5. So, based on that.
PAUL: the results also. So, all the initial documents that is being written from there. So, K is equal to 10 total, retrieve documents, and the re-rank number is 5.
PAUL: Yeah, so generally, like, on top of 50 retrieved documents, I pick up the top 20, so that has become a very, very common standard.
PAUL: Alright, now there is a language chain implementation, so, I feel that right now this is under the deprecated version, but there is a cross-encoder rankle. It has been moved into the language, but as you guys know, most of the deprecated things have been moved to the classic version, so probably in future, it might be deprecated.
PAUL: Okay, so from here, actually, like, you can take this particular implementation, and you can do it. So, directly, this implementation, I've kept it.
PAUL: And I think, in our Llama index, it's much better, because for post-processing… see, whenever you look into a post-processor, you have to think about this is a second stage retribut that happens. So, the LAMA imports are much more meaningful as compared to lan chain. So, here.
PAUL: Kuhar rank. So, in simple terms, I don't want to use Kohar, really, guys. So, you can simply commit this out, or if you want to take one API and you want to really do the testing. Otherwise, you can simply pass it here.
PAUL: So, this is the Llama Index version that I have provided. So, simply, you can test it out. Now, in Langchain, there is no LLM-based re-ranker in Langchain, but in Llama Index, you have this one. Llama Index Porth Processor, LLM re-rank.
PAUL: Okay, so this option is available in your Lama Index, where both the LLM re-ranker is also available, as well as the cross-encoder. But in LanChain, only the cross-encoder is available, okay, but you have to do a manual implementation of the re-ranker.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Everybody, please try to do your executions, and then let me know. Because for today, I think this is the only part I won't be discussing anything
PAUL: when should use re-rankers? It's totally… it depends upon your reserve, it's not when, like, I feel that… I don't use re-rankers really a lot, okay? And,
PAUL: I don't make…
PAUL: It was not my decision, actually, I've gone through multiple academics, and in some cases, I feel it's good, because, actually, when I showed you this example, it becomes much more meaningful.
PAUL: Okay, so if you remember this particular example, so when I really look into this, I feel that somehow… because if I ask this query, what is the capital of France, do you really think your keyword match, your sparse, will work?
PAUL: Neal spots.
PAUL: Your sparse will work, how many of you think your sparse vector will work? It will never work, because there is not the keyword only, the actual keyword that I was looking for, which is sparse.
PAUL: Okay, so in some cases, but again, there are much more advanced academic papers, okay, from where we get to not read, I think, okay, it's an optional thing, but it's not really free. If you want to really go ahead, okay, that paper part…
PAUL: Okay, if you want that, okay, I will share the link, you can actually… Go through this particular paper.
PAUL: Okay, so we're ranking free, rank.
PAUL: Okay, replacing re-racking with selection in rack for sensitive tubes. So, this paper is somewhere, I feel.
PAUL: Because really, like, papers, really a lot of papers are there, but little bit game changers actually happen.
PAUL: So, from who does that, I actually get it.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, coming to, some, like, if I directly search, okay, so some, get me… Okay, so, first, UD ranking…
PAUL: Modeled growth that you're learning.
PAUL: Okay, so something with respect to re-rankers, okay, now…
PAUL: Power operator anchors, again, models have been defined, I think, again, they have taken.
PAUL: They have not taken such one. What is the model that they have taken? Pinecone. Pinecone has its own re-ranker model. It means that they host the model in their own environment, and based on that, they throw, but never use that. Okay, there is a BG re-ranker model, yes, this is also good from the BG family.
PAUL: Because I think Thursday I'll be taking an extra class, okay, and that extra class, little bit with respect to unimodality, also, I'll be talking about.
PAUL: Because that part is not in your syllabus, but I feel that it is important. And if you really want to go through, this paper, this paper is also interesting read, if you really want, like, lost in the middle.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a fundamental approach from where, like, re-acting actually played a very crucial role.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: There are so many papers, like.
PAUL: If I start giving, it takes a lot of time, but really, this is a good one.
PAUL: Mmm, I think directly, top 7 rankers, if I really look into… Mmm…
PAUL: Okay, because… oh, yes, this is an enterprise-level Kuhar LDAC. Like, this is the best one. Like, blindly, I can trust it. It means that I don't, but again, that comes with a price.
PAUL: That's the main thing. And this is actually faster. The response time is also good as compared to sentence transformers-based open source models. Don't know they have done some type of optimization, so that's why
PAUL: Like, even I don't use the LLMs of CoShirt, but really, for relanking, I feel that this is a good option.
PAUL: movie data. It depends, like…
PAUL: in a day, it's not about, like, I only pick up 2 to 3 papers in a week that I go through.
PAUL: And generally, the entire paper, you don't need to read. You need to go through the abstract, then comes the core stack in the paper, and then look… you have to look into the benchmarks. Nobody read the entire papers.
PAUL: There are a certain part of a paper that only you need to focus.
PAUL: Okay, so Thursday, I'll be keeping class from 9pm to 11pm, okay? So, in that, I'll be discussing few things with respect to that unified company.
PAUL: Dear.
PAUL: Okay. Now, if you want to apply RAT to Tamil languages or Sanali, in simple cases, like, you have to first look into that, parsing mechanism.
PAUL: No, Wednesday. Wednesday, already I have a class for the Ultimate Data Science Batch, so really, I cannot go through.
PAUL: Benchmarking, I think, LLM benchmarks are there, no? LLM leaderboard, that website, you can directly search, Rajat and you can get it.
PAUL: LLM leaderboard, Velam…
PAUL: LLMStats.com. Okay, that is, like, a better one, I feel. You can always go through, I'm sharing the link.
PAUL: Alright, Mintage, if it is fungal, nothing I can do.
PAUL: Tuesday… Tuesday also, I can take the class, I have no issues. Tuesday also, I can take it.
PAUL: Okay, so simply just wait, I will raise a poll, and you guys can let me know whether Wednesday or not.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: Where is the pole, pole, pole, pole, pole?
PAUL: I think I need to create a new poll.
PAUL: I'm so flothered, only two options…
PAUL: Come on, weekday, does the…
PAUL: Okay, the timings will be fixed, because that is my time.
PAUL: Alright, now choice one will be, visiting…
PAUL: Okay, and then finally you have your Thursday, because next week, I'll be starting a little bit with respect to Text2SQL, because from Monday… from next Sunday, the second project, I am planning to get it.
PAUL: Okay, so I will be launching, let's say, as a webinar goal, okay, extra class launch, okay? So everybody let me know, like, Tuesday or Thursday.
PAUL: Alright, what we'll be discussing in that extra class?
PAUL: We'll be talking a little bit with respect to this hybrid search model.
PAUL: Something others that I feel that…
PAUL: It needs to be discussed in lesser places people talk about those things.
PAUL: How much time is my speed? Maximum… 30 minutes, 30 to 40 minutes, not more than that.
PAUL: And it can be in parts, it's not necessary, okay? So, like, in one shot only, 30 minutes, some part, I keep it as a book month, that's fine. Next week, it will be text to SQL, and then we will start our second project.
PAUL: Second project also, also, because right now, the thing that I've already, taught you, hybrid cells, after project 2, directly, we will jump into your, the third one, the third project. So, few projects will be simultaneously, because third project was hybrid brand.
PAUL: Let's see,
PAUL: Everybody, like, I think, out of 150 folks, 110 folks have voted, rest 40 folks, I'm not sure what they are doing. Okay, so simply, I will end the poll. I think I have given enough time, more than 1 minute, to do the completion, and simply, like, let me end the poll and share the results with you.
PAUL: The majority is it with Thursday, right? So, I'll be going for Thursday. I will end the poll, and I will share the results, okay? For transparency.
PAUL: My major LLM… yes. My major… my only LLM I love is Claude right now.
PAUL: I love a little bit of GLM. I don't know how many of you use GLM 4.7. That comes from Z.ai. That is actually good. I feel it's cheaper also, if you're actually planning to use. And then comes the Minimax K21.
PAUL: That is the other one that I feel in OpenSoul version, it's really good. These three, actually. Deepsake? No, Deepsake.
PAUL: Deep silk is something, like, it always comes, but really not a fan of deep silk.
PAUL: SLLM. SLLM, I… what is SLLM? I'm not sure about.
PAUL: Mayan won't be joining, I think. Okay, so Mayan won't be joining. So, right now, just to share you the stats, okay, so when I say about…
PAUL: You have to understand, with respect to the stats, my stats are always… because in the month of December, a lot of game-changing things have happened. Even LLMs are deprecated. I know… don't know how many have heard about VLM Jepaka.
PAUL: That's right. So, LLMs, I feel like they will be deprecated with respect to time, but, again,
PAUL: Let me just… this is, I think, advanced with respect to my screen theory. Again, so the stat I was talking about.
PAUL: Okay, so if you really look into Gemini 3,
PAUL: I've worked with Coding and other stuff, Gemini 3, really bad. Okay, not up to the mark. Opus 4.5, this is just like…
PAUL: my favorite model, okay, at any point of time. Gemini 3 Flash, not a fan of this one. Again, CBD 5.2, okay, okay. Then you have this, GLM 4.6 and 4.7. So, I feel that the GLM 4.7 is really good from Z.Ti. You can actually check it in Christmas, they are really good offers.
PAUL: Okay, if you try to compare their pricing with others, and which is Minimax M2.1.
PAUL: Really, this is also good. But,
PAUL: Really with respect to actual, because though Gemini 3, if you ask simple thing with respect to complicated code, reasoning is, really, I don't feel it's up to the mark for Gemini 3. Whereas Opus is like, Claude, that's why I…
PAUL: Claude.
PAUL: is, like, my favorite, okay? Can you see any list here, here? Because GPT-5.2, again, this is a costly operation. Okay, and GPT-5.1. So, like, OpenAI models are not really so much good.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that the market is much more, dominated, and if you really look into DeepSeek, can you see even in the top 14, people were telling DeepSeek?
PAUL: Okay, so, like, a few things are there, again, with respect to deep OCR, deep-seq OC OCR, I feel that that OCR is really good, but again, not every point of time that, deep-seq is there, okay?
PAUL: Asian workflows introduced by China. Okay, alright, yes, I feel that the Chinese are much more smarter. They work on the core tech. It means, let's see, Chinese guys are really good in reverse engineering.
PAUL: And sometimes they try to write much more efficient code as respect to hardware.
PAUL: Whereas I feel that that is lesser done in some other places. The level of optimization that is done in…
PAUL: Assembly language level.
PAUL: See, really, assembly language, if people are working with, that is…
PAUL: Nobody… that is the highest level of optimization. Okay, that is what those guys actually work on.
PAUL: Well, I feel that, yes, that is better, because the entire approach and other things will change.
PAUL: I think Vijay, right now, this… in this course, we won't be talking about that probably the next course.
PAUL: I'll be launching… because even I will be taking your inputs, because what should be in the next version of RAC code that I'll be launching? All the inputs from your guys, so, like.
PAUL: 50% decision I will take, and 50%.
PAUL: Agent Crag is there in this syllabus only, Mudassan.
PAUL: Why you are telling that in your next syllabus you need agent decline?
PAUL: Agent grab is, again, just think about a landing function binded inside a function call. That's the only thing. Agents, I'm not really a fan of agents. It makes your life much more easier, but actually, in a product, it's just like a very small service.
PAUL: Couple of that do the research, VLJP,
PAUL: Alright, now, in this case, will all our learning be worthless? I would say worthless.
PAUL: See, I have been seeing the field of data science from 2016. I feel that the fundamentals I know, that plays a very crucial role in decision making.
PAUL: So, you should know the fundamentals. Everything. So, probably after, in 2030. Can I say that these things that you are learning, this will become the fundamentals?
PAUL: To bring some new tech on top of that.
PAUL: Everything, with respect to time, everything becomes the fundamentals. It means that today it can be something in advance implement, but after 5 years, the thing that you have learned, it will become just like a fundamental thing.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: All right, guys, so majorly, this part is done. Okay, because there are other things in the notebook, if you want, you can explore query transformations, I think, after the project discussion that I'll be talking about. Because those are prompt-level tasks.
PAUL: Okay, so you can actually, if you're interested, you can go through the notebooks. But on Thursday, okay, a little bit different, because till now, I don't think, you guys… you guys have done anybody using a single model? Have you done your DELS embedding as well as your sparse embedding?
PAUL: So, little bit about that particular approach, okay, I'll be talking about. It's an old approach, but again.
PAUL: I feel that somehow it's safer. Not everybody uses that in the research community, it's famous much more, rather than in product.
PAUL: Should things.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just stop sharing. People with questions, they can simply come, and they can ask.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just stop sharing my feed. Murtaza, Mudasa Rakim, Deepa, Nitesh, everybody I have unmuted.
Murtuza Saifee: Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Hmm.
Murtuza Saifee: You're good.
PAUL: Yes.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, April, thanks, thanks for the session. So actually, I just stuck, on one of the understandings regarding this RRF flow. So, I just want to validate the understanding with you, because that's where I got confused. I'm not able to connect all the dots.
Murtuza Saifee: So let's say we have a large corpus of documents. Let's say we have PDF. So now, what we start with is we start with our…
Murtuza Saifee: parsing, and then we, let's say, chunk all those data. So let's say we got around 5,000 chunks for those, or let's say, 1,000 chunks, for a simple calculation.
Murtuza Saifee: We got those chunks. So what we do after that, we prepare the embeddings for that, dense and sparse, right? For those chunks.
PAUL: Once you have all the chunks, you will be calculating the scores for all the unique chunks found.
Murtuza Saifee: No, so we didn't insert it yet in the vector store yet. We didn't done the retrieval yet.
PAUL: Okay, you have not done that part, okay, fine.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, so we just did the chunking, now we do our dense embedding and our sparse embedding, right?
PAUL: Is that it?
Murtuza Saifee: both the embeddings will, let's say, store in separate, separate collections in the vector store. One collection is for my dense vectors.
PAUL: In a single collection, you can see.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, so single collection or two collections, let's say.
PAUL: deals.
Murtuza Saifee: We stored in the vector store now. So now, we got the user query. User query, we pass it into the vector store. We got, let's say, top 20, results from the retriever.
PAUL: Alright.
Murtuza Saifee: So these are top 20 chums.
PAUL: Correct.
Murtuza Saifee: Now, this top… top 20 chunks that we got it. So, from that part, how we apply this RRF? So, now these chunks are chunks, so, like, we, I just got the chance. Now, again, I will do my, sparse embedding and the dense embeddings.
PAUL: No, no, name reading is a one-time thing only.
PAUL: Whenever he was… I don't fix it properly.
Murtuza Saifee: 20 chunks. Yeah, I got the 20 checks for the retrieval.
PAUL: Oh, yes.
Murtuza Saifee: How would it processed after that?
PAUL: For 20 chunks, let's take the example of a dense rate triple. In dense red triple, you'll be getting the score by… based on similarity. Similarity scores, it will be sorted, like, from top to bottom, high to low. Okay, now that becomes a rank.
PAUL: for you, in the case of DES. Similarly for sparse also, the values with the higher, they will be highly.
Murtuza Saifee: not just.
PAUL: lower, they will be lower than that. Okay? Now, when you are actually doing… now, for example, in your RRF, you are taking 20 for now. In 20, like, probably, you might have got, like, I'm telling… your total chunk, what was the total chunk?
Murtuza Saifee: Let's see… the one which I ingested is 1000 chunks in the.
PAUL: Okay, 1,000, okay. Now, so generally, out of those 1,000, in those 20, it is not necessary that all the chunks will be the same.
PAUL: Okay, but…
Murtuza Saifee: In both.
PAUL: Yes, in both. The chunks won't be the same, but if both the chunks are appearing, they will be highly boosted. Because of that, they will be getting hashed.
PAUL: If it is not there, it means that simply it is not found in dense rank. For example, out of those 20, probably the 7th channel. Okay, like C7, if I say that, that particular is not available in your dense search only. So, simply, it is not found there, only it will look into that sparse rank. So, automatically, that value becomes 0.
PAUL: It will only…
Murtuza Saifee: Got it, too.
PAUL: It will include only the sparks.
PAUL: rank part, and it will take it in the RRF calculation.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, so yeah, that's what I was confused, like, it is necessary to have the both similar chunks, because it's not possible to have similar chunks in both the results.
PAUL: Miller chunks is not possible.
PAUL: the idea is always, sometimes even what happens, if I have seen in some implementation, people are applying different chunking. Okay, a little bit different chunking on this one, on 10 steps past.
PAUL: Okay, so in that case, actually, they calculate the unique chunks. Only they look into, first of all, they will sort what are the unique chunks, and only on top of that, only they apply RNAs.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, so filter it out from those two retrievers.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, so… so from the query, we retrieve two outputs. One is from dense, and one is from sparse. Either we combine it, or either just calculate the RF based on whatever the values that we got it from both the retrievers.
PAUL: Yes, so simple. Like, in major cases, I will say, like, if you'll boot the list.
PAUL: out of 20, in your example, probably 10 might have, and 10 is not there only. So, for the 10 which is not available directly, the value will become 0.
PAUL: Okay, and only the one which is happening, it will be added.
Murtuza Saifee: Got it, got it. Yeah, this is what I was… I was missing.
PAUL: So, simply always remember, if in both those places, even in your retrieval, in your sparse retrieval, also, you were getting the same chunk, as well as in your dense retrieval.
PAUL: In both the cases, the values will be added, so the boosting mechanism is much higher, if it is found. If it is not found, there will be, like, no boosting. Simply, it will be of lower value only.
PAUL: So that's why the practice is you should take always the top K more whenever you are doing these type of approaches. You should not…
Murtuza Saifee: It'll be more prob…
PAUL: The probability will be more high on getting those relevant ones.
Murtuza Saifee: Got it. Got it, thank you.
Nitesh: Yep, apologies.
deba: I was also having the same question, yeah, so the server has opened up. Only one point I'd like to add…
PAUL: Because I had opened up that, right?
deba: Yeah, the same question I had, I had… the dots are now connecting, but one… one thing is, for example, if the user is putting a long text into the context, for example.
deba: Then, is it necessary to embed that text, before we go for, you know, search on the… in the retrieval we are doing the searching, right? So, whatever.
PAUL: kind of, if…
deba: Every day.
PAUL: there is putting…
PAUL: First of all, how the user will put that context you put it. I'm taking… are you referring to query?
deba: Any normal query, or text, yeah. Any questions?
PAUL: You… see, you are asking question. Potion means query only, context means query.
deba: Yeah, yeah.
PAUL: chunks, basically, that's why. Okay, anytime, embedding has to be applied. Without embedding, you cannot do it.
deba: Oh, that's a must, okay, okay.
PAUL: This is classical NLP.
PAUL: Classical NLP tells us you have to always create an embedding function.
PAUL: Which is orthogonal in nature, as well as injective in nature.
PAUL: According to mathematics.
deba: Okay, then only the real retrieval will come out, right? Either it is Danes or Sparts, whatever, right? The real… the actual…
PAUL: It will do the similarity search. It's not about dense or sparse. It will simply do that similarity search.
deba: Yeah. So the similarity search algorithm is going to be applied on top of VectorDB for the query that is coming out from the user, and the user query also has to be embedded first, and then only the search will take place, right? If I'm getting you correctly?
PAUL: Quotion is confusing. First, you told the user will put it, see, at any point of time. For both the things, you need embedding, whether for the context or whether for the query.
deba: Okay, okay.
PAUL: Without emitting nothing, we cannot do any type of search operation, whether an, like, based on Ethiadian distance, Jacquardium distance, any type of distance operation is not possible.
deba: Got it.
deba: Thank you so much, Jim.
PAUL: All right.
Nitesh: Hey, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Then, after April.
PAUL: Nitesh?
PAUL: Model Zhar.
PAUL: Yes, I can hear you.
Nitesh: Okay, okay, I'm not sure what went wrong. Thanks, thanks for the session, and I probably had almost the same question what the Murtaja had started with.
Nitesh: But I just wanted to understand, when we do a kind of a, the document uploading or the chunking, like the initial, the data ingestion pipeline I'm talking about.
Nitesh: Do we need to create the two different vector stores, one for sparse and one for dense, or maybe if we can have one same data store or one same collection.
PAUL: It will be inside the same collection only, you know? Yesterday, I showed you the example.
Nitesh: Yeah, so, but then they do two different kind of embedding, wouldn't it be?
PAUL: Two different types of embedding you can save inside a collection.
PAUL: Yesterday, I have shown you that example, no? In that Melbours part in split.
Nitesh: Yeah, we had only, yeah, the same correction, I understand. But my question is coming from there only. So, generally, when we talk earlier, we always say the embedding, the model which you use while retrieving and while data ingestion, should always be the same.
PAUL: I was telling Vector Store will be one, but, can have different collection. No, no, no, collection will be the same.
PAUL: All right, I'll see. Just wait, because this part, really, with respect to, in your project, it will become much more clearer, but I feel that, just yesterday's implementation, I will show you.
PAUL: Okay, so… just a quick recap of that one. Just for your inferencing part, I think… where is my… this one? This is the advanced pass embedding, okay? Now, let me close it. So here, when I defined my collection schema, if you remember.
PAUL: Okay, so this is parse through matrix. Okay, now this is a collection schema. In that collection schema, I am having multiple fields.
PAUL: Okay, can you see here? First of all, I have defined, okay, so one very specifically for BM25 vector, that I have kept it. Similarly, I have another one for split vector.
deba: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, you can have multiple vectors, there is no issue in that, in a single collection.
deba: Okay, okay.
deba: Okay.
PAUL: But… Just be sure, yeah, it feels like during the ingestion, you have to always maintain that.
PAUL: Suddenly, you say that, okay, I don't want to insert one field very specifically, then in some vector databases, it becomes a problem. Just, it means that only on top of field, only one. In some databases, it doesn't support. In milliverse, you can do it. In quadrant, you can do it, but in QTBs, it's not.
PAUL: Okay, but the core idea in a single collection, you can always save multiple vectors, doesn't matter.
Nitesh: Okay, so when the concept of having a same embedding and same dimensions while Retriever, we should use it, I'm a little getting confused there, because…
Nitesh: I'm…
PAUL: I see.
Nitesh: If you have Sam.
PAUL: within a main list, you have two different lists. One list is having different dimension than the other. Do you think that it impacts the core
PAUL: data type. It doesn't help us.
Nitesh: Okay.
Nitesh: Oh…
PAUL: If you want, practically, you can test it out.
PAUL: Okay, if you want them, probably on Thursday, I'll be showing you that. Okay, or probably I'll be keeping it. Just one simple cell operation.
PAUL: Not, something, like, easily it can be done. In the next class, I'll be showing it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If you feel that.
Nitesh: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, I'll be taking the example of quadrant and probably one from Chroma. Now, I'll be doing that operation, and I will show you in a single collection, you can keep multiple vectors.
Nitesh: So, on the same follow-up, like, when we are doing a query and, like, going for a retriever, so when I'm going for a retriever for, like, a sparse retrieval, so does it go and, only search into the sparse vector, or maybe, like, the displayed vector? And when we do a.
PAUL: When we'll be doing the search, we'll be tilling on top of which field within the collection it will be doing the search.
Nitesh: Please come again, I just missed it.
Nitesh: Yeah.
PAUL: Within a collection, you can have multiple fields. So, for example, within a collection, you can create multiple lists.
PAUL: So, I'll be telling that, okay, for this, like, every list when I'm talking about, it means that there will be some header that will be attached with that. So, where I will do the search, very specifically, I will say that, okay, within that collection, through this header, access this particular list of numbers, and then do the search on top of that.
PAUL: It's a simple logic, it means that with respect to code.
Nitesh: So, oh…
Nitesh: I got it. So basically, while we're designing the system, from the start itself, we have to find whether we want to…
PAUL: You have to plan that part.
PAUL: What exactly has to be there?
Nitesh: Oh, God.
Nitesh: Right, and then, every time whenever…
Nitesh: The new document… document ingestion is happening, it has to go in both the… both the vector fields.
Nitesh: With the two different opinions.
PAUL: CACSS for every document that you will be maintaining. So those will be separate
PAUL: Actually, like, p-value pairs, in simple terms.
Nitesh: Pipelines.
PAUL: Yes, for every document, then you'll be saving in that way. Like, for this document, this is the sparse vector, for this document, this is the delvector.
Nitesh: Okay, good, good. So, thanks, Paul. So, I think we would be covering this in a part of the project, too, or, like, advanced rack, the pipelines.
PAUL: 3. I think in the hybrid rack project that you have.
PAUL: See, you can directly, I think, you can look into the implementation in my GitHub.hybrid rack project is there. From there, also, you can take it, but we'll be going through, it's a simple thing, okay? If you want, probably in the next class, it's just a one-cell task hold.
PAUL: If you want, I can shoot it.
Nitesh: Okay, thank you, thank you, this was my question.
Nitesh: Yeah. Thank you both.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, highborn?
PAUL: Next.
PAUL: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, Paul, I have, one question, related to LLM, timings. So, for example, like, we have…
PAUL: No, Murtha, just wait, Murta is asking the best approach either. No, no, no, no. It's a common, everybody saved within a single collection only. That is a standard.
PAUL: Collection-level differences, we create in a different level. It depends upon the business use case.
PAUL: Okay, so generally it's a common practice to save within that. Okay, so let me a little bit talk about tatters.
PAUL: So, yes, in the meantime, you can go ahead with your question.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
Rajat Khanna: So, my question was related to, like, we are using our RAG pipeline, and in the production, we want to maintain a log as well. Log as in, like, this many chunk size has been created, or these are the, range, that, semantic search and all those things. So, like, log that we want to maintain. So, is that also more time-consuming on LLM? Like, we are not maintaining
Rajat Khanna: log, then log, then the LLM will give us faster results, as compared to we are maintaining some logs.
PAUL: maintaining some logs from what prospect that you were telling?
Rajat Khanna: Just, like, these chunk size, we have created, like, these many documents we have done, by giving the path of the document, chunk size, like, we are implementing the cells, and by cell by cell, we get our results.
Rajat Khanna: So, by the same way, like, we want to store all this information in the log, so someone who is, reviewing that pipeline, so he don't have to go through the code, he just go through the logs.
Rajat Khanna: whatever the model that we have used, it also, in the log that we are using, maintaining, whatever the chunk size, dimensions, all those things, it's just maintained in a log. The person don't need to go through the code.
PAUL: I will write… So, means what after that? This is a simple implementation, like…
Rajat Khanna: No, no, it's simple.
PAUL: Keep it at the config file route.
Rajat Khanna: Nope.
Rajat Khanna: more time?
PAUL: No, no, no, no, there is no such, thing. It will take more time.
PAUL: Because this is a code-level implementation, and really, it's not about… your rack process will be affected. There is nothing related to that. Otherwise, why people will use logging?
Rajat Khanna: Okay. And, the other question is related to, like, we are using re-ranking, so for, like, we have, enabled a,
Rajat Khanna: we have done our chunking, and then retrieval is done, and then on top of that, we are doing re-ranking. So, is there a process where we do… we use different rag pipelines, and then by that RAG pipeline, two different rag pipelines, and then there is some… another model, we implement on those two different rag pipelines, and appropriate result
Rajat Khanna: will be shown.
Rajat Khanna: Like, there will be two different drag pipelines with two different models, and then.
PAUL: Really, the question that you were asking, why you need two different rack pipelines, first of all.
PAUL: I could not understand. Generally, the pipeline will be single. Two different rack pipelines.
PAUL: For a single query, if you want to do that approach, yes, you can do that. It means that if I am talking about two different pipelines, if you have from there, you'll be getting the top K, top K. Okay, add that K plus K, and then on top of that, if you want to apply a re-ranging, that is also fine.
PAUL: Practically, architecturally, simply possible.
Rajat Khanna: No, it's possible, but do we do it? Is it advisable?
PAUL: It depends upon a use case. Directly, I cannot say that it is doable or not. The thing that you were telling you is doable, but do we have such a use case?
PAUL: I don't feel I have worked on such a use case, but practically possible that you work there.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, yeah, that's it. Thank you both.
PAUL: All right. Okay, as I was sharing the screen, okay, so always have a look, because when you look into the pricing of any vector databases, I will be showing it to you for Milbus also.
PAUL: Zbs, actually, not for members. So, this part, okay, can you see, like, this is a rough estimation I have taken. I think I have taken close to 1 billion. Okay, let's make it 1 billion, 6 zeros. 1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3. Can you see, what is the monthly cost that is coming for a vector DV?
PAUL: See, I have taken everything optimal here, okay? 1536, open embedding, so really, if you just increase… I will just increase this dimension. What is the price that I'm getting? Everybody please have a look, because this pricing part…
PAUL: Like, actually, if you're doing a cost estimation from here, generally, you can look into. 2638…
PAUL: Okay? Now, let me change the vector dimension. I will make it 3072.
PAUL: Is there an impact in the cost?
PAUL: Till now, I have not done any auto-scaling and other thing.
PAUL: Okay, now this parse vector, so this is basically for split data I've taken, but really, you have to understand that both the things, parse vectors and test vectors, so it can come within a collection, and based on that, only the pricing that comes around.
PAUL: Okay, so simply you can have multiple collections. From those multiple collections, the total number of dense vectors and the sparse vectors will be calculated. So, like, it can be separate, you can keep it, but I feel it is not optimal way of doing it. Because for the same data, it is a bad practice to maintain two different collections.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, the data representation, the actual original text, is the same. So, generally, it's a bad practice. And really, like, these are some common charges I am telling on a monthly level.
PAUL: Similarly, Zilli's as, only based on vectors. It doesn't matter whether it's a dense vector or it's a sparse vector. Directly, it charges. So, like, Zilith's calculator also, I will show.
PAUL: The little close pricing, I think, from here, compare plans, somewhere, I think, yeah, cost estimation, here.
PAUL: Generally, like, vector DBs are really, really costly, okay? Now, most of the time, serverless, it's a bad practice to go with serverless, because these are not dedicated clusters. Every organization needs a dedicated cluster, so I will go with a dedicated cluster.
PAUL: Okay, and now, there are multiple optimized, the performance optimized, so here, generally, you keep 1.5,764. Now, based on that, they have multiple, the capacity optimized.
PAUL: TAR storage. So, most of the times, I feel that their inferences are much more, but if I go with performance optimized, okay, and right now comes the number of entities.
PAUL: the entities matter, so let me take one… okay, so, this one. Okay, this is the maximum number of entities it support, I think, 10,000, and let me change the vector dimension to 1536.
PAUL: Okay? Now here, the field map. Okay, the field schema, basically. On top of that, you can select each field.
PAUL: Okay, like, which field you want to have, and based on that, you can actually create a character. Can you remember I created a collection schema yesterday in Zillis?
PAUL: Not in Zales, I created in PyMus, but very similar. It means that BL.net, you can actually create. Like, in most of the cases, I'll be using, float, okay, for my, embedding.
PAUL: Similarly, the another will be float.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And based on that, like, I think somewhere the…
PAUL: Okay, they are not showing you an estimated cost per month, but it should show.
PAUL: I think, standard plan, capacity optimized.
PAUL: this part directly. Previously, they used to show this particular figure, but I think they have removed that one.
PAUL: I feel, because of this one, okay, now I think the number of entities are much higher.
PAUL: Okay, so let's reduce the number of entities to 21.
PAUL: Now, this is a rough estimation call that is coming.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, like, vector TVs are really costly if you actually use it in production.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, you can understand, if it's a startup, then generally for enterprise organizations, this bill doesn't matter. And always remember, this will scale up with respect to time.
PAUL: Like, $1,000, $2,000, like, very, very cheap stuff, I guess.
PAUL: So always decide, like, we always take this consideration, so when you design a vector DB schema, we take the pricing for at least next 3 years for what will be the… based on that, we prep up a rule, okay, and then we proceed.
PAUL: Others, please go ahead, I think Moduser, I've given you access, you can speak.
PAUL: Guys, please… JB has raised, I think, JB…
JB: Paul, can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes.
JB: So, in sparse embedding and dense embedding.
JB: We got a chunk, and chunk 1 intense embedding.
JB: We got the rank of 1. We're trying to look for the same chunk in the sparse embedding, what is the rank of it, right?
JB: In RSF bundle.
PAUL: Correct.
JB: Mapping happens, like, from…
JB: this chunk one in dense embedding, we're looking for some same chunk in the sparse embedding, right? What is unique identified.
PAUL: Louis, don't look for the same chunk, first of all.
PAUL: We don't look for the same chunk, we just look into the output of the dense retrieval and the output of the sparse retrieval. There may be the chunk in both the cases.
PAUL: That's only, I explained.
JB: Like, Paris is a capital of France, that's in… that's what we got in the… Spa somebody.
JB: For Paris?
JB: You forgot.
PAUL: laddies.
PAUL: You are talking with respect to Sentils right now. I'm talk with respect to Frank and schools in some buildings.
PAUL: Don't talk with respect to sentences. That is not a valid way of doing this discussion.
PAUL: The simple way you can say that, okay, I got my tense results, I got my sparse results, okay? Now, probably, from there, I'm looking into the top 10.
PAUL: ops paths, and opt-ins. Okay, now, probably, the chunk can be there in test. Okay, so probably from here, I got the top 10. Now, here, you got probably chunk A. That chunk A might not be available in your spur search. Automatically, that value becomes 0.
PAUL: I want to say you had your term.
JB: When you say chunky is not oil business spouse, how are you saying that? There must be some I didn't favor it.
PAUL: There is no identifier, it means that in the top case, search it is not there.
PAUL: In the dens, you are getting chunk 1, like C1 to C20. Later on, during sparse, that thing will change, you know?
PAUL: How it can be exact is what you are thinking, first of all, tell me.
JB: Yeah, so the top chunks in the… Suppose C1 in dense vector.
JB: We're trying to find this even rank in this pass.
PAUL: So, you are thinking that C1 here, it will be there, and C1 here also, it will be there.
JB: Yeah, somewhere it should be the red, but with a different ranking.
PAUL: is the rank will be different. If it is not included in the top 10, automatically that value becomes 0.
JB: Okay.
PAUL: If it is there, it will be taken into account. That's why I told you, if the same chunk appears in the dense search as well as the sparse search, the values will get boosted, because the addition operation will take place in one of the cases if it is missing, wherever, in whichever, like, in dense if it is missing, or in sparse. Automatically, that value becomes zero.
PAUL: That's the thing I'm telling you.
JB: Okay.
JB: I got it, yeah.
PAUL: C.
PAUL: It cannot be that your dense result and your sparse result are exactly the same.
PAUL: It can never be possible.
PAUL: Algorithmically, mathematically, anyhow, it is not possible.
PAUL: The ranking of the chance has to be different.
PAUL: Okay, probably, if your query is in such a way that it's keyword matching exactly to a certain thing, it means that directly a thing from the content that you have picked up. Okay, so for sure in that case only, but those are very rare case scenarios.
PAUL: It means directly one sentence you copy it from one of the chunks, and you make it as a query. In those cases, only that will be high. In other cases, it won't be such high.
JB: Yeah, makes sense. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, let's move to the next participant.
PAUL: Modasar, again.
PAUL: JB is done, so I will disable, device also done. Disable talking.
PAUL: No, Taza, no response from your side.
Mudassar Hakim: Sorry, Paul, there was some technical glitch. So…
Mudassar Hakim: First of all, thanks for the session today, it was helpful. I think I kind of got what the…
Mudassar Hakim: Just fast overall. I needed another help here.
Mudassar Hakim: with respect to case studies, more specifically towards RAGs, for example, there are blogs, right? I normally go through blogs, where companies post
Mudassar Hakim: their experiments, their outcomes, their achievements with respect to using LLMs, with respect to Gen AI. And they share insights, you know, how what worked for them, what did not work for them.
Mudassar Hakim: But right now, I know it's a little bit scattered for me, I just… if I get to know them, I get to know them while going through some…
Mudassar Hakim: post through LinkedIn, maybe, or Reddit, or somewhere or the other. Do you have some kind of a good mechanism or a central pool where I can explore more of these blogs or case studies? Maybe…
PAUL: See, generally, like, always look into the market leaders who are there. For example, with respect to vector databases, you can look into the blogs of Quad, right? You can look into the… their concepts are also there, and few client use cases that you will be getting.
PAUL: But again, it's not like that, they will be just discussing everything in high level. Correct. Nothing with respect to architectures and those things. They will simply say, this is our client, they use this one, and based on that, they applied this one in that way. So, every product, you can look into the major products with respect to rack tech stack.
PAUL: Okay, now, you can visit those websites, and you can actually go to, like, client use cases, and most of them, they have it.
Mudassar Hakim: So, my example is like this, okay? One of the URLs I've shared in the chat, where Uber does share, you know, time to time, some good technical articles of how things have worked for them, what they are doing today.
Mudassar Hakim: Right?
PAUL: Super use case, similar DC. Now, every organization doesn't… does it, first of all.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, exactly.
PAUL: Netflix will have, very specifically. Few of them done it, but you have to do that particular research. There is not a single place you go and you get it.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, that's what I'm saying. I'm right now, kind of, subscribed to company blogs where I get to know where things are happening. I was wondering if there could be some centralized place.
PAUL: Nothing is…
Mudassar Hakim: created list.
PAUL: If somebody is doing it, you can create such a product, if you feel. People… that's how alphaSignal.io works. They have created a product. Every day, they send the newsletters to everyone with respect to the AI updates and other things.
Mudassar Hakim: Alpha Signal AI, is it?
PAUL: alphasignal.io.
Mudassar Hakim: alphasignal.io. Take a second, I'm just checking.
PAUL: Those are not company use cases, those are only technical product, like, technical updates with respect to research papers, it can be with respect to news, those things that comes. Nothing related to use case. Few things it can be, but I feel very less use cases.
Mudassar Hakim: Alpha Signal I.O, is it?
PAUL: Yes, alpha Signal.
Mudassar Hakim: Interesting. Something else. I'm getting Bitcoin, Ethereum, and all that stuff.
PAUL: Just search Alpha Signal. Alpha Signal is a very famous, I can say.
Mudassar Hakim: Oh, I got Alpha Signal AI.
PAUL: That AI only, I think, then. Okay, because alphaSignal.io previously, they might have changed the domain. When they launched it, ESA, this one. This one only.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, you can directly just do a sign-up, and every day you will be getting information. But nothing related to use case, these are much more news stuff in the AI world.
Mudassar Hakim: new things happening in the AI industry.
PAUL: AI volunteers, that's the main thing. And there is another guy in,
PAUL: substack, that guy is AI dis… disruption.
PAUL: Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: Now, this is the other one, mainly a Chinese guy is there. Okay, now he also shares a lot of updates with respect to very technical things.
PAUL: Okay, so at any point of time, this is also good.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, I mean, these are good stuff. These are good stuff. But I think, kind of curated, blog post,
Mudassar Hakim: you know, something would be nice, but fine, if it's not there, maybe I can try giving it a shot. Really, that kind of repository is not there out there.
Mudassar Hakim: But just sort of checking with you once.
PAUL: Mmm, because Jenny, I am subscribed to those things.
PAUL: Just to get a news, like,
PAUL: you can do that, but little bit of web search, another thing that matters. Medium, I'm not a fan of Medium.
PAUL: Majorly, all good authors have moved from medium to substack.
Mudassar Hakim: What was it? Medium…
PAUL: That's why I'm not a fan of Medium. Medium, yes, back in 2021, 2022, but from 2024, the major shift among major authors is to a subset. If you are actually looking into research part.
Mudassar Hakim: Corpus.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay. Because I think company blogs are still kind of using.
PAUL: Company plots are there, but, really, like, with respect to implementation level, not such much, but yes, with respect to high-level architectures, those things you can get it.
Mudassar Hakim: Fair enough.
Mudassar Hakim: Cool. Thanks, Paul.
PAUL: No rate.
PAUL: Tara Verma, you have raised your hand.
saurabh verma: Yeah, I want to share my screen to share the project work, which I was talking.
PAUL: Not right beforehand.
PAUL: Now I have added it.
PAUL: Hurry, substack, substack, Dev.2 is also better, at least.
PAUL: Which one? Dev?
PAUL: dev.qvo.
saurabh verma: dev.dio.
PAUL: do.
saurabh verma: to you.
saurabh verma: So, Repal, you said we can connect, separately also, so let me know how to connect, but just.
PAUL: Okay, now this is much more details. I will probably go through a meeting.
PAUL: Okay? Because, I think that will be much better.
saurabh verma: Yeah, yeah. So, how should I contact you?
PAUL: Just drop me a mail, I'll be sharing you my calendar link.
PAUL: Okay.
saurabh verma: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, yes.
saurabh verma: And, yeah, okay, okay, thanks.
PAUL: Probably Tuesday only, then I will connect at night. I am free. I think other guy also, Suhan was there, E2317, okay, so I will respond to him also.
PAUL: and wisdom. Terrific.
saurabh verma: Email, email, you have not shared, no?
PAUL: Email is there in Notion, the first thing in Notion? Okay, in the.
saurabh verma: There you go.
PAUL: But only, it is available.
saurabh verma: Yeah, take per minute.
PAUL: Alright, it's app at the rate Krishnag.in, as simple. App, application, app at the rate Krishnag.com.
saurabh verma: Okay, okay.
PAUL: You too.
PAUL: Just search AI disruptor Mengly, Substack, Kiran Kumar, okay, you can get it. Akili Babu, my question, got on scaling, okay, alright, ask your question, so…
PAUL: With respect to scaling, Akhil Babu, Akhil Babu, yes, Akil.
PAUL: Tell me, like, scaling-related issues.
akhil babu: Yeah, regarding the scaling, I have some, you know, internal questions from my view. So, they want to understand that how we'll do the scaling for the RAG applications.
akhil babu: With respect to the… Capacity, and with respect to the number of users, and with respect to
akhil babu: Solely.
PAUL: What is the current user stack that you were telling? See, like, scaling means, first of all, how many users are you targeting?
PAUL: Target audience size.
akhil babu: Yeah, they have given a instance, let's say, 1,000 users for its applications.
PAUL: Hmm.
akhil babu: So, based on that, the dimension has to be given to them. So, it is a kind of a MBP kind of thing, they want to do it, correct?
PAUL: Here, scaling really, like, if anything you pass one lakh, then probably I might say move towards
PAUL: that one, EKS-based, like, Kubernetes-based solutions. Right now, it's not even one leg, so engineers can even handle anything close to one leg.
akhil babu: Correct. So, what are the key points we need to check? Can you, have some reference links, somewhere?
PAUL: there are no such things with respect to racked scaling, because this is much more from DevOps side. Because we create the containers, we create the service. Later on, they take care of that scaling part.
PAUL: Okay, probably, like, if I'm tailing about, most of the times, if I'm working with Farget, automatically, Farget handles that, if it needs to launch and other things. If I need more and more scale, because Farget, again, it's a costly service.
PAUL: then probably I'll be hosting a Kubernetes cluster, and then on top of that, because EKs and other hosted Kubernetes services are also very costly.
PAUL: But for your initial purpose, it's pretty much container-based solutions that can actually help you.
akhil babu: Yeah, no, maybe, that means ACS and AKs in Azure actually stack, they want to, you know, try to understand.
PAUL: Because in Azure, it is EK. Similarly, in container-based services, in Azure also, it will be available, for sure. Because really, I don't work with Azure a lot, but in Azure, for sure, it has to be there. Because I know EK is there. Similarly, Google Route GK is here EK is the same service.
PAUL: Actually, but generally, I suggest Kubernetes if you surpass that 1 lakhtz per second, generally.
PAUL: Okay, if anything less than that, really, NGINX can handle it.
akhil babu: Correct, yeah. If you can help me, because tomorrow I have a call, so…
PAUL: Maybe in this case.
akhil babu: So, if you can help me, any documents or reference, because I have to prepare today night, and tomorrow I have a, you know, on-call with them, actually, with the leaders. So, that is the reason I was just… because they want to hear from me.
akhil babu: So I don't have a fair idea about that.
PAUL: First of all, you have to look scaling in database level, because vector databases also need to be scaled. Okay, then comes your application level scaling. In that way, you have to look into what are the things that needs to be scaled, first of all.
PAUL: First of all, you have to look into the services, then based on that, you have to decide which services need to be scaled. You need to break it down, and then finally, based on that, like, because most of the times I have seen, like, even with respect to vector databases, also, they host it in.
PAUL: Kubernetes cluster. So, that's why, a separate service. But generally, if you're building the entire solution, everything you can keep in a single EKS cluster, and you can work through it.
PAUL: I don't think anybody has that. This is much more related to ops directly. I don't have that document, or anything like that.
akhil babu: Okay, okay.
akhil babu: But, fine.
PAUL: first of all, select the service, then based on that service requirement, always look in service level. Like, database also needs to be scaling. Vector database also needs to be scaled.
PAUL: Okay, how many replicas you want of that particular vector database, or for any type of Postgres also, anywhere, or for Mongo.
PAUL: like, whenever you look into, first of all, select what are the services. Then, actually, you can go to the pricing page, and you can get a rough estimation. But with respect to, if you want to set up your own infra, then it is different. Then, actually, you have to look into certain cloud services from Azure, then only you can tell that, okay, now these are the main ones.
akhil babu: And mostly, for the security outside, they would like to hear also, that means when you are,
akhil babu: creating, suppose your banking system is there, suppose a project is there. So they don't, you know, prefer, actually, on-premise kind of things. So, how the dimensioning, you… That you guys prefer on-prem?
PAUL: I have worked with many banks, they always prefer on-prem, they don't prefer cloud.
akhil babu: Teddy.
akhil babu: Perfect.
akhil babu: And, how is the selection, model selections, and all those things?
PAUL: In that case, we'll be generally going with open source models, you will be using, like, OpenA and others. You'll be looking into what are the best open source models, and then you'll be picking up from there.
akhil babu: So we'll not go for this, Lama and other things, no?
PAUL: Lana can go, Lama is open source, you can actually use it.
akhil babu: Yeah.
akhil babu: But not OpenAI, 4.0 or…
PAUL: you will be using, because at some point, you will be sending the data to OpenAI, though they say they have all the security standards, HIPAA compliant and others, but really, like, with trust level, I cannot say.
akhil babu: Yes, yes, that is.
PAUL: Because for banking, entire bare metal, because in banking, I know we start from bare metal.
PAUL: We take the bare metal, we do the setup completely from scratch.
akhil babu: Hmm.
akhil babu: That is, and with respect to the optimizations, with respect to the RAG application optimizations.
akhil babu: So, what are the steps, winning, any…
PAUL: certain data steps, the optimization is an incremental thing. In one step, I cannot say these are every.
akhil babu: Yes.
PAUL: filthy.
PAUL: That comes with respect. Once from MVP you move to much more… once the user will start getting much bigger and bigger, slowly you try to look into the cons, and then you try to improve your system. In one short, I cannot say. But yes, there are certain things with respect to vector DB operations and other things that.
akhil babu: Hmm.
akhil babu: Okay, okay, okay. No, fine, fine, fine then. We got you, actually. Your sessions are really helpful. Thank you for whatever, we are having to know. It is very helpful. I'm referring that. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, nitesh, again, you have raised your hand. Yes, Nitesh.
Nitesh: Hey, hey, Paul, I think I just wanted to contribute into the conversation in the last we were having regarding the on-prem decisions and all. So, I think I need a recommendation there as well. So, I'm working on a kind of the same kind of a project, where my team is responsible to create a platform.
Nitesh: on-prem platform, where we're probably hosting, multiple LLMs, and providing as their gateway
Nitesh: For all our users to having a unified access to different LLMs. So that's what we are currently working on. So, the one thing which I was, like, missing out is that
Nitesh: Is there any recommendation, like, if you want to provide a kind of a capabilities for our users to build Iraq systems, or maybe a different AI applications, is there some recommendations that these are the 5 to 6,
Nitesh: LLM models and embedding models, we definitely host there, so that would be a more generalized, or probably can…
PAUL: See, generally, like, if you are hosting, it means that you are not going with enterprise-based solution.
PAUL: Okay, so whenever you are looking into, always go into the main reference of number of users for a particular model. You can always get that information from Huggingfield. From there, you can actually look into what are the top re-ranking models with the number of downloads.
PAUL: From there, we actually take the reference that, yes, this is widely getting used in the community. And based on that only, we do the selection, and then we try to host that.
PAUL: We always look into the usage. It's not about we pick something which is very less used, but very good. Rather than we pick something which is widely used.
Nitesh: Okay, so I'm understanding from the conversion, anyway, the enterprise, like OpenAI and all those we cannot really host by our own, right? So we are using only open source, models, which we, like, through NVIDIA, through Cloudera, and through different,
Nitesh: The provider which we are… which they are helping us, or like Databricks. So, they are helping us to get the model onboarded, and hosting them onto on-prem itself.
Nitesh: So that's what I was looking for, because we have to balance out the compute, like, we do not have the… so many of GPUs, probably, which we can take all of the repository of all of those models of LLMs available out in the market. So, we wanted to select maybe top 10, top 9, which can solve almost all the use cases, probably, like RAG and QN-based AI system.
Nitesh: Or, like, the coding-based AI system. So, that's what I was looking… the right… right balance, to create some kind of a tracker, or… or kind of a… kind of a same board as a leaderboard.
Nitesh: And put all the details there and see these are the most commonly we want to select. I mean, some selection criteria, basically, if there are some recommendations that way.
PAUL: Not your point. So, that particular information, you can always get it, like, from Hugging Face is the best place, from there, you can actually
PAUL: take all these references by the number of downloads, and actually, it's easy only. Majorly, the families that comes around, okay, the Mistral family, really very good. The DeepSeek family, okay, it's good, I can say.
PAUL: Then, similarly, the Lama family. These are the common families which are widely hosted.
PAUL: around everywhere.
PAUL: If you look into the solution that you were trying to build in, and just try to compare a competitor.
PAUL: Okay? For example, if you take Nebias, if you take Saman, they do the same thing that you were talking.
Nitesh: Sorry, can you come again, those names? I mean, I can just check them.
PAUL: Ambanova Cloud is there, Nebius is there.
PAUL: really, the list is very long. If you look into LLM providers, gateways, you will get a very long list. Even Open Router is one of them. Okay, the list is very… really long.
Nitesh: So, from there, you will actually get, these are the top 15 to 16.
Nitesh: Okay.
Nitesh: You mean to say the open source one, right?
PAUL: Correct, total source one.
Nitesh: Okay, okay, okay. Probably, I will go through it, and we'll connect maybe in the next session or somewhere, if I have follow-ups.
Nitesh: Something…
PAUL: And always, like, decide the models based on a few parameters, okay? For example, the models which are fastest, the models which are cheapest, the model which is having the lowest consistency.
PAUL: This, like, based on these few factors, we actually take decision.
Nitesh: Hmm.
PAUL: Okay, so you have to actually search, like, for.
Nitesh: Maybe.
PAUL: the fastest models with respect to the Llama family is Llama 4 Scout.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, you have to do that particular research, and then actually you can come up if you're actually selecting the top 10. So, based on latency, other factors also comes into the picture, like when you are hosting, how much GPU is required, those things with respect to hardware infrastructure. A lot of research is required in it.
Nitesh: And token size comes into the picture there as well, like, context, window, size…
PAUL: Yes, every LLM has a fixed contact size that you need to always take care of.
Nitesh: Okay, this helps. I mean, this gives me a good start. Thanks, thanks, Paul, I think, this helps.
PAUL: mode rate.
PAUL: That's true.
S K: I'm April.
PAUL: Yes.
S K: So… I was going through various different, workbooks.
S K: When I looked at all the implementations of Lang Chain and Llama Index with different functionalities, there are some things that are available in line chain versus Llama Index, just for example, re-ranking that you were mentioning today.
S K: Is there, like, a cheat sheet, or a…
PAUL: Nothing.
S K: that prolong.
PAUL: comes with practice. When you do implementations and you do the comparisons annually.
S K: Correct. I'm trying to do that, and each time I'm marking it down, putting it in a notepad or Excel, trying to see all these things, but with your experience and expertise, I think it would be much more easier to just
S K: you can recall most of them. I don't do so much that, and…
S K: Believe me, at this point in time, this is all for learning purposes, because there will be teams and teams of people who will be doing that.
S K: So I don't look dumb, I'm going through this stuff. But would be really helpful with your expertise and experience that you have done hundreds and thousands of implementations.
S K: Could you prepare something for us that will really help each and every student in this class?
PAUL: This is really, like, right now I'm talking about Lansh, and probably next I will come to Haystack.
PAUL: So, really, framework doesn't matter to me.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If something is not available in a framework, I will do a custom implementation. Every developer does that.
PAUL: Okay, the poor thing is the concept behind it. And even, when I teach one concept, the implementation can be 5% different in Llama Index if you try to compare it with Langen, even with respect to prompt definition in a certain implementation.
PAUL: So, like, I have never created, neither I have learned anything in that.
PAUL: that if it is here, if it is that not there, should I take a note? And I have never done it that way, true to say.
PAUL: If it is not there, quickly I will write my own custom function, and I will create a custom
PAUL: like, whichever component is required, and I will attach it. That is my approach. So, really, like, creating a list, what is available in LanChain, what is not available, really, there are more than one lag functions, so…
PAUL: It is not doable for me.
PAUL: That's why. I hope you get my point. From a developer perspective, when you look into the deep dive of a library, it is not practically possible.
PAUL: Just to do every comparison on that.
PAUL: high-level component, things only that I can say.
PAUL: Okay, but again, not completely with respect to the like data. Very, very hard.
PAUL: There is no such… I don't think anywhere you can get a resource also for that.
S K: when I'm going through this stuff, I am also facing
S K: issues with the functionalities, that you write the code with so much ease, and you provide us the notebooks when I'm trying to do it on my end. I always have to go through Cursor or some LLM to create that code.
S K: I'm not able to do anything of that. As an example, you created some boilerplates from GitHub or individual
S K: websites that you took and quickly created them. What I do is I take those things and put it in LMM, and then ask
S K: To look through the stuff, but now that… We already have…
S K: Microsoft Copilot, it is getting a little bit easier as well. It runs through the code along with me and tells me where the issues are. But how are you able to create all those stuff?
S K: All those codes, notebooks…
PAUL: Gently, for my content creation.
PAUL: See, I don't use the OpenAI stack. My stack can be on Mestral or on Anthropic. These two are my major LLM providers.
PAUL: Okay, I don't use OpenAI, like, the OpenAI family in some cases is good, but really, for deep research, I can say DeepSeek is good.
PAUL: Anthropic is good.
PAUL: Because it comes, like, I do multiple experiments with multiple LLMs. Simply, I know that most of the times, OpenAI fails.
PAUL: if I give a very complex type of coding problem.
PAUL: Okay, so I know that, so with practice, it comes at, okay, I know that for specific tasks, I will pick this one.
PAUL: And majorly, like, true to say, like, Sronet, Opus, it does the job, but comes with a cost.
PAUL: If you look at weather into curse or weather for OneShop, the token price
PAUL: as compared to, like, OpenAI family, or, any paid one, if you take, events up, there are SWBench, some custom models are also there. But always remember the
PAUL: highest one, the most costly one, is Anthropic.
PAUL: They take the most amount of money, even more than it.
PAUL: So, the quality of Anthropic models are the best in the market.
PAUL: But again, from my perspective, as a developer.
PAUL: You have to understand. If I change that developer to some other role, again, I won't feel that it will be good.
S K: Alright, thanks.
PAUL: Generally, I also manage my context window. It means that I handle what is going inside the LLM, what is coming out of the LLM. I have rules written that this needs to be followed.
PAUL: as a context, so a lot of other things that I do generally for content creation. Just think about 3 months back, if I want to…
PAUL: created a content. Just, if I want to go back in that stage, if I want to resume something, for that, I do create checkpoints.
PAUL: Because I know that in your batch, I've taught something. Probably in the next batch, also, I need to teach. I need to manage the context.
PAUL: Okay, because otherwise, again, I have to do from scratch all the things that I have done. Even I might forget. Even the developers, anything after 3 months, you ask them in this component, what you have added, nobody remembers.
PAUL: So, it's just that way I have made my workflow.
PAUL: I hope you get it.
PAUL: Alright, let's see, it's much more about practice, simply. Like, from the developer perspective, like, day-to-day, for 3 months, if somebody is dealing with language, he or she will be good.
PAUL: There is no doubt, like, he will know majorly all the boilerplates, all the import, what has changed in every version, everything. Similarly, like, when you used to work a lot in PyTorch, in Keras, we used to keep a track, because as a developer, it's their job.
PAUL: Okay, so it comes, so nothing is there, but yes, little bit with practice, that's the only thing I can see.
PAUL: Alright, so I think there are no more hands raised.
PAUL: So, guys, Thursday, session, 9pm.
PAUL: IST to 11pm. I'll be talking about that unified model concept. It was not there in the syllabus. Little bit unique approach, an old one, but I thought about, let's discuss that particular approach also.
PAUL: Alright guys, so happy everyone, thanks for joining. Let's meet on Thursday for our discussion.